<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>log.andvari.net</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://log.andvari.net/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://log.andvari.net/</id><updated>2021-01-03T01:23:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>January 03 2021</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/january-03-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-01-03T01:23:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-03T01:23:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2021-01-03:/january-03-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20210103-shelly.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20210103-shelly.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now most of the way through the ~month or so I took off work. Around the start of it, I made a few plans, but I also resolved to unapologetically spend much of it just relaxing, and feeling non-guilty about that. It's something I've been working on, and I'm …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20210103-shelly.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20210103-shelly.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now most of the way through the ~month or so I took off work. Around the start of it, I made a few plans, but I also resolved to unapologetically spend much of it just relaxing, and feeling non-guilty about that. It's something I've been working on, and I'm fairly pleased with the results. Sometimes the things you do are for you. It's one of the things I know and then steadfastly refuse my own counsel on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the outcomes was solving a few of the outstanding home and home automation things I've been loking at doing for ages. The above is a &lt;a href="https://shelly.cloud/"&gt;Shelly 1&lt;/a&gt; connected to the pinout of my garage door opener. I didn't have much say in what kind of opener and ended up with the kind with an Internet of Shit widget that just doesn't work properly, and a Manufacturer that don't take too kindly to hobbyists by not publishing any schematics. Thankfully, I happened to know that shorting two of the terminals on the back worked the same as a remote control press, and here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the outcomes (unplanned, but here we are) of this break was that i've started writing code agin in earnest. I hope it lasts when I go back to work; I partially credit &lt;a href="http://www.adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt; and some nice folks over on the &lt;a href="http://irishtechcommunity.slack.com"&gt;Irish Tech community Slack&lt;/a&gt; for that -- but i've picked up on some other stuff as well. (btw, my attempts up until I ran ot of time are on &lt;a href="https://github.com/gerrowadat/adventofcode/tree/main/2020"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, including practicing on previous years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I guess if this is the last entry for another year or two, you'll know how going back to work went).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>December 31 2020</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/december-31-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-31T15:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-31T15:40:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2020-12-31:/december-31-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20201231-homeassistant.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20201231-homeassistant.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last attempt at doing the Home Automation/Domotics/Whatyacallit a few years back mostly involved buying expensive widgets, determining they are shite, or marketed at US power and outlets, and then discovering that setup and upgrades generally involved one ore more of downloading a random .exe from random websites …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20201231-homeassistant.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20201231-homeassistant.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last attempt at doing the Home Automation/Domotics/Whatyacallit a few years back mostly involved buying expensive widgets, determining they are shite, or marketed at US power and outlets, and then discovering that setup and upgrades generally involved one ore more of downloading a random .exe from random websites, soldering, or tracking the ongoing battle between hardware manufacturers and hobbyists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, things have gotten a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; better in the last few years. One of my personal projects in the time off over xmas this year was finally fiddling with &lt;a href="https://www.hass.io"&gt;Home Assistant&lt;/a&gt;, which got done on the houses's brand new &lt;a href="https://www.k3s.io"&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; cluster (but, more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been, quite honestly, a breath of fresh air. I might be a little unhappy with HA devs racing to the bottom in terms of what market to cater for (but that's purely a selfish concern), but it's...refreshing to see an ecosystem of support build around something. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also helps that manufacturers like &lt;a href="https://shelly.cloud/"&gt;Shelly&lt;/a&gt; are openly suporting offline use and flashing their kit to something like &lt;a href="https://tasmota.github.io/"&gt;Tasmota&lt;/a&gt;. One of the key concerns last time was just how flakey it all was - and subject to the whims of manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm still working on the trickier parts of integrating the random assortment of Internet of Shit devices at home, but this is a very promising start.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>December 09 2020</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/december-09-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-12-09T01:28:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-09T01:28:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2020-12-09:/december-09-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20201209-brainwork.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20201209-brainwork.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've set both a really good example (take your vacation!) and a really bad example (Don't leave it all til the last minute!) for work folks, and therefore today was my last day at work in 2020. It's been a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I'm especially looking forward …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20201209-brainwork.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20201209-brainwork.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've set both a really good example (take your vacation!) and a really bad example (Don't leave it all til the last minute!) for work folks, and therefore today was my last day at work in 2020. It's been a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I'm especially looking forward to this time round is taking on projects and doing things in an active way -- a lot of the time, my primary complaint when I take some time off is that I get to the end and feel like I've wasted it. I often feel like I can't get things done because there's some crucial thing I need to box all my time off for. A few months back, someone casually remarked to me that that sounded like burnout. So, taking this time was one of the things I wanted to do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other was actually going and doing something about some of the ways my brain worked. That means drugs and therapy. I'd done some advocacy work (where I could) at work around mental health, and even while I was doing that, I kinda realised I felt a bit hypocritical, because I was basically untreated (aside from a few abortive attempts to go to a therapist that amounted to being handed a burned CD of whale noises and being told to google &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_behavioral_therapy"&gt;CBT&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, long story short, I've been back on SSRIs (I was on them for a brief time about 10 years ago), and I'm seeing a much more engaged and useful therapy person. It's been pretty great, actually. I feel a lot more like myself again - like a version that isn't really struggling as much, without the mind racing constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the side-effects of this, of course, is that I've started to write code and do some wee projects again. I hadn't felt up to this in a long time. Probably years. It's a good feeling. What's helping right now is &lt;a href="http://www.adventofcode.com/"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt;, but I've also got a few things going at home. Hence the picture of the haul of RPi stuff -- which I do intend to write some more technical posts on, as I progress. A month off is long enough to form some good habits; maybe logging more stuff is one of them? No Promises :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my list is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RPi cluster to replace an aging NUC machine, probably running &lt;a href="http://www.microk8s.io"&gt;MicroK8s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some Shelly lightswitches (they run over WiFi, and can be flashed with &lt;a href="https://tasmota.github.io/docs/"&gt;Tasmota&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably other Zigbee stuff, assuming it arrives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fiddling with &lt;a href="http://www.home-assistant.io"&gt;HA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also fiddling with &lt;a href="http://www.mycroft.ai/"&gt;Mycroft&lt;/a&gt;, possibly as a replacement for Google Assistant (Nothing against it as such, but I do want more stuff to work when we've no internet at home).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I note at this point that I do tend to go big or go home on hobbyist stuff. A month is a long time, let's see where we get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But first, some decompression. And to put up the tree.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>November 22 2020</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/november-22-2020.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-11-22T19:08:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-22T19:08:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2020-11-22:/november-22-2020.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short a quick trip to Zurich in January 2020, the trip I was on was the last time I travelled outside Ireland, until now. I also don't plan on going anywhere until mid-2021 or thereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as all that's been written about how this year has been, one of the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Short a quick trip to Zurich in January 2020, the trip I was on was the last time I travelled outside Ireland, until now. I also don't plan on going anywhere until mid-2021 or thereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as all that's been written about how this year has been, one of the largest lessons I take away from it is that it called me and many folks in probably a similar position on some assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would happen if you didn't have to go to work every day? Either because you were a remote worker, or just because. You'd have more 'time in the day', fewer excuses about getting exercise and eating healthy, and so on. Notwithstanding that COVID has been a terrible experience for pretty much everyone, after a certain point you have to get to something like normalcy, and see if it's what you expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I put on a load of weight, didn't really leave the house for a few months, and went back on SSRIs. I found a good therapist and I've mostly got the extra few kilos back off again, with more to come. It took a while but I think I am adjusting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always had in my mind that I'd take some time off before I retire. By 'some', I mean maybe a year or two. It always seemed strange to me that people would work until they're in their late 60s, after they've lost the ability, freedom and inclination to do the things they can't do because of work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an imaginary expectation that if I suddeny didn't have to go to work any more, that fulfilment and relaxation would fill the gaps -- in reality, I really hadn't thought about it all that much. If I stopped working tomorrow, I would enjoy the situation for...maybe a month? Two months? I'd then have to do something. My platonic ideal had been having nothing to do, and now I know that just makes me anxious :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past 9 months has been a microcosm of that. My last almost 20 years has been me being on the road every month or two, and that's all gone now. Do I miss it? Honestly, no. I enjoyed some parts of travel, there were good experiences; but I'm really not crazy to get back on the road again. I could take or leave business travel, honestly. I often said before that the amount of business travel I do kinds ruins holidays for me - the minute I go near the airport I'm in work mode. I'm trying to manage the situation, and getting stressed about everything going smoothly, and waiting for the trip to be over so I can go home. So in some ways I am kinda looking forward to travel for travel's sake again. But, I can wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could write more words about the future of work than will fit here -- I think this year has been an accelerant to that progress, but we are heading toward a brick wall where we have to deal with the social nature of humans and how we can't substitute that with technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Same time next year?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="catchup"></category></entry><entry><title>November 09 2019</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/november-09-2019.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-09T14:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-09T14:14:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2019-11-09:/november-09-2019.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20191109-choochoobrains.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20191109-choochoobrains.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been over two years, and while I'm still patiently waiting for the demise of &lt;a href="http://www.medium.com/"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, it only took re-running &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;pelican-quickstart&lt;/a&gt; to make my makefiles work again. Plus we haven't deprecated serving static content just yet, so there's that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the selling points for blog platforms these days is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20191109-choochoobrains.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20191109-choochoobrains.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been over two years, and while I'm still patiently waiting for the demise of &lt;a href="http://www.medium.com/"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;, it only took re-running &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;pelican-quickstart&lt;/a&gt; to make my makefiles work again. Plus we haven't deprecated serving static content just yet, so there's that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the selling points for blog platforms these days is some sort of federation thing, or the promise that more people will read your nonsense, or other stuff that's nothing to do with producing an actual log. It's something LiveJournal got right, in a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, I'm on a train from work on Seattle, to San Jose, which is also near work. In a toss-up between getting a 2-hour flight and sitting on my ass in the bay area for two days, I choose....22-hour train journey. It's being a pretty good opportunity to switch off, when these are few and far between these days, more than I'd care to admit. The very fact that I'm on the (offline editing) blog thing will give you an idea of the extent of the problem I have with disconnecting :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I last took the &lt;a href="https://www.amtrak.com/coast-starlight-train"&gt;Coast Starlight&lt;/a&gt; maybe 8 or 9 years ago, that time from Oakland to Los Angeles. I remember it as a fascinating drive-by of some of the smaller parts of American life -- as someone who's really never visited the USA for pleasure purposes, it's easy to forget it's where millions of people live in small towns, and rolling past and getting a look at that brings me a sense of ease that even with an open text editor (the modern equivalent of a notebook), I can't properly try to express with words. It's a good feeling and I'll take it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trip to the Pacific Northwest, short as it was, was also a good reminder that it's a place I enjoy being at. Maybe it's the weather? Or the closeness to nature in the planning of the city. Anyway, it puts me in a mind to having a go at coming here for nonwork reasons. That doesn't happen a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayway, that's yisser lot. Like always, I promise myself I'll update this more, if my brain is in the space to do so. And, most likely like always, it never bubbles to the top. Seeya when I see you :-)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="catchup"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>An Update on Life</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/an-update-on-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-06T11:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-06T11:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2017-02-06:/an-update-on-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last few months have been a bit hectic, let's say that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In work, a few things happened. I got promoted to 'Director', which is the top end of the management progression, bottom of executive. What either of these mean, I'll probably never know. About a year or so …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The last few months have been a bit hectic, let's say that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In work, a few things happened. I got promoted to 'Director', which is the top end of the management progression, bottom of executive. What either of these mean, I'll probably never know. About a year or so ago, I expressed a bit of existential angst about how my job had become more about pottering about among the various pies I had a finger in, making generally well-meaning statements and giving advice. I felt like I wasn't getting a lot of work done, frankly. My boss at the time said "This is what a Director does", and that was a bit terrifying. I guess now I know what it feels like (all over again) to go from full-time engineering getting-things done to management, yet done in some other stratum. Your tolerance for delayed gratification has to go up another notch, as the stuff I'm up to now has a 3-5 year timeframe, as opposed to yearly or so, as opposed to quarterly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's been fun times thus far. Trying to find the balance between getting stuff done, and being hands-off. I honestly think getting this balance right is one of the primary things that stands in a middle manager's favour - the balance between getting stuck in and not letting the people under you grow, and feeling like you're not really doing anything. It's also a very situational thing. Every time I've gotten promoted in the last 5 years or so, I've thought "Right, that's me I guess. Topped out.". What this means in my head is that I've honestly no idea or concrete advice for other folks who want to go down the same path. Every Director I've ever spoken to about it had a different story. They're not going to tell you how to do it, they can only tell you how they did it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing that happened is that I guess I'm now head of SRE for Dublin. Again, this role means different things for different people - I'm not terribly figurehead-y in some ways, and I'm lucky to have lots of great folks around me to make sure I get mercilessly taken down a notch if I'm doing not enough or too much of things. I'm also happy to be back into the 'existential terror' mode of operation. I believe everyone should be reasonably sure they can do about 80% of their job. The other 20% are what keeps it interesting. This only happened a month ago, so I'm still figuring it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Home&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of stuff here as well! I am adulting very much, after a few years of not so much. I am generally bad at adulting so this is good, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, and I guess most significantly - myself and my partner of 8 years now live together properly and for realsies. There are various and sundry private reasons why this wasn't the case, and the thing that happened to make this happen is also private, but this is a big deal for me - sharing my life with someone else in so complete a way is a new thing for me (yes, despite being nearly 40, I've never actually lived with someone I was going out with). This has done wonders for my general well-being, in many, many small ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Semi-related - we're selling the house I bought almost 3 years ago, and moving into Dublin city proper. This was something I was thinking about for a long while, and the above thing also precipitated it. There are a couple of reasons why this is happening now, which I guess are relevant to most commuter-town folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reference, I currently live about 40km outside Dublin, and I work in about as far east (i.e. the opposite end) in Dublin as you can. I commute by car or motorbike mostly, and it takes about an hour, at best. I've been doing this for 10 years. I had figured this was worth it, as I like having privacy, space, and so forth. Also, the way the property market is, you get about twice as much bang for your buck compared to living in Dublin. Even if there were houses and gardens the size of our current place in Dublin, you're talking most of a million quid, whereas we're selling up for not even close to half that, and doing well out of it. Things are amazingly Dublin-centric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the reasons break down to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commute finally killing me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's getting worse rather than better. Economy is recovering, lots of people have cars and need to use them. My commute took 45-50 minutes on a good day 2-3 years back. right before christmas, I had a few days where it took over 2 hours. Fuck everything about that noise. I think having the motorbike took the sting out for a bit, but I realised back in the middle of last year that I was literally driving into Dublin every day, including weekends. Why don't I live there? Good question, obvious answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health (mental and phyiscal).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live along a main road. There's nowhere to walk if you don't like being run over by a truck. You have to drive everywhere. What this meant in practical terms is that I got little to no exercise, unless I made a point of it, drove to a place, exercised (walking, cycling, etc.), and then loaded up and went home. Back when I lived in Dublin before and moved out to the country, I distinctly remember putting on about 10kg just by missing out on the walk to the bus stop or down the shops. I spent a good chunk of the last 2 years getting literally no exercise. Walk 10 feet to the car, into and out of work, then that's it. I've put in about another 10kg in the lat 2 years, with really no sign of it slowing down. There was really only one way that was going. I'm not a gym person, and I find it very difficult to rationalise or will myself to get exercise that doesn't have a 'point'. I'm the least physically fit and heaviest I've ever been right now. I'm getting to an age where that's actually pretty dangerous. I'd rather wake up now than in a few years when I have my first coronary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, it's just secluded. I don't have an active social life. I went to a pub a few weeks back on a whim, and realised I haven't done that in probably a year or more. All the folks I'd go to the pub with are either work peope, or live in Dublin. I already have pretty severe social anxiety, that isn't getting helped by living in a hermitage. So, even if it makes me a bit uncomfortable, something has to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services for peope who live outside cities and large towns are getting worse, rather than better. Ireland has always been a city-centric (and specifically Dublin-centric) country, and this shows no signs of going in the other direction. Broadband is pathetic (I get about 50Mb on an LTE connection, with a 20GB per day download limit). In the last few years, getting tradespeople to come out to a place has gotten harder as the economy picks up. Case in point, my electric gates broke down a few weeks back. The original installer said "I won't be able to come out to you for at least 3 weeks", and replied "dunno" when I asked what else I could do. Rural Ireland is kind of fucked. By that I mean living outside towns. I could move down the road a mile and probably do a lot better with services - the appetite to go the last mile is just not there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because I can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been pretty lucky in that I have a job that pays well, and I really don't have any outlays or expensive habits (aside from Airsoft kit, which granted isn't that expensive in the grander scheme of things, if you compare it to golf or something).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have the ability to live in Dublin, that I perhaps less so had 10 years ago, when I first moved out. So, it's time to embrace the privilege a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, all these reasons got written down sometime last year, and we started looking, as well as putting our place on the market. It sold reasonably quickly, and right now we're going to rent for a bit and take our time. I'm going to have to get used to some stuff I used to take for granted (being able to walk! to a shop! public transport! taxis that don't cost 80 quid!), and I'm looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, all of the above manifests itself as my being a ball of abject stress for probably the next 6-12 months. But, it'll all be worth it, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>Everybody's Free (To Use Their Best Judgement)</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/everybodys-free-to-use-their-best-judgement.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-26T11:22:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-09-26T11:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-09-26:/everybodys-free-to-use-their-best-judgement.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is something I wrote for new Googlers, drinking from the information hose.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(With Apologies to Mary Schmich)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen of the Noogler classes of $YEAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use your Best Judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could offer one tip for your present and future career, it would be this: Robots can be …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is something I wrote for new Googlers, drinking from the information hose.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(With Apologies to Mary Schmich)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ladies and Gentlemen of the Noogler classes of $YEAR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use your Best Judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could offer one tip for your present and future career, it would be this: Robots can be taught to follow policy and do things mostly properly, and you’ve been hired because you’re empirically not a robot. The rest of this advice has no basis more reliable than my own meandering experience...I will dispense this advice now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, treasure, and fully use the time you spend being useless. Oh, never mind -- you won’t appreciate that time until a year from now, when you’re the subject of an innocent but terrifying question about GSLB or something. “I wish I had time to read about GSLB and play with it so I’d know this stuff, even though I don’t deal with it every day,” you’ll think. Your uselessness will pass, embracing it by learning breadth-first opens up more possibilities than you can possibly fathom. Being too useful too early means there’s no going back to full-time, wide-open learning. Don’t try to be useful because you’re wondering if you’re fired. You’re not fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there’s a lot to think about and learn, remember that even if we had the technology to insert facts into your brain, the facts are not what we’re interested in. We’ve already got lots of those. We’re interested in how you apply them, and how you deal with them changing, sometimes quickly and unexpectedly. Knowing things is normal. Doing things is skill. Invention is Art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get out of the office sometimes. In fact, get out a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Respect useful precedent, but challenge the status quo. One of the best questions a new person can ask is “Why is this the way it is?”. One of the worst responses to being told “Just Because...” is acceptance. If you don’t get a good answer, keep asking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to someone from another team occasionally. Chances are they’re either doing something way better or worse than you are, or you have problems you didn’t know you shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get enough sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that if co-workers think differently from you, it probably means they’re better than you at something. We’re all here because we’re curious about the world, and want to do the right thing. Despite what your Sunday night terrors are telling you, these people you’re thinking of don’t spend their free time steepling their fingers and wondering how best to make your life difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Occasionally wonder if you’re one of those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’ll stick around a long time, maybe you won’t. Maybe you’ll work on the same thing for a long time, maybe you won’t. Maybe you’ll be telling people to get off your lawn 10 years from now, smiling knowingly as people charter projects to deprecate technology that is the New Hotness today; in favour of The New New Hotness. Be humble; your experience is a responsibility: to stay hungry, to pry yourself out of pigeonholes, to do the right thing. Any day now, a new person will ask “Why is this the way it is?”. Have a good answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy is as powerful as Code. But remember that most Policy was written for and applies to the general case. Think about why we felt we needed one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept certain inalienable truths: Software has a lifecycle; there will always be a features/stability tradeoff; there will always be a moonshot happening; we will never be finished. Someday you’ll find yourself yearning for a simpler time when this wasn’t the case. Were you paying attention?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend 5 minutes away from your desk, really thinking about what made you happy this week. Write it down. Do more of that next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day is a school day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As obnoxious as it sounds, there really is no substitute for being right, and empirical rightness is the most effective form. Be patient in explaining yourself, and remember that the definition of “right” can also change (sometimes it’s “cheapest”, sometimes it’s “whatever doesn’t drive your team insane”). Sometimes it’s just as hard to figure out the question as it is the answer. That’s why you’ll never be replaced by robots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that, above all else, we’re here to do the right thing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Trust me on the Best Judgement thing.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Writing"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>Conferences for Introverts</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/conferences-for-introverts.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-08-20T17:29:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-08-20T17:29:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-08-20:/conferences-for-introverts.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is a paper I wrote for consumption of people doing conferences and trainings at Google. I figured it was more generally applicable, so here it is)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conferences for Introverts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Update: September 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preamble: What is an Introvert?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this out of the way first so we …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is a paper I wrote for consumption of people doing conferences and trainings at Google. I figured it was more generally applicable, so here it is)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conferences for Introverts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Update: September 2015&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preamble: What is an Introvert?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get this out of the way first so we know what this document is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Introvert’ is an overloaded term. It can mean anything from pretty much its direct meaning (which we’ll get to in a minute), to the stereotype of the sullen teenager or loner. For the purposes of this document, we’ll use this definition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Introvert is someone who regains emotional energy from being alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extrovert, as you might guess, is a person who gains energy from interacting with others. It’s that simple. How a person ‘recharges their batteries’ is a personality facet that usually doesn’t change much, and is pretty difficult to try to change on purpose. Thinking about it for a second, you can probably tell which you are. Humans seem to be roughly split down the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I say that most engineers are introverts, please know that I’m not making any pejorative as to what they’re like. All I’m saying is that they need certain things to function well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What this Document is&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a collection of tips and advice on how to run a successful gathering (i.e. conference, training, offsite) for a set of people who include introverted people (hint: that is most gatherings). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why I should Listen to You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Dave. I’ve been at Google since 2004. For most of that time, I’ve been an Engineering manager. I was a junior one, and then I was a senior one (I started as a junior sysadmin, I’m now a Director). I am enormously introverted. I will actively avoid talking to people I don’t strictly need to talk to. I am stupendously inept at small talk. I’m okay with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the usual bouts with imposter syndrome that we all face, the idea (knowing myself as I like to think I do) that I interact with, talk to and manage people for a living is a deep and powerful mystery to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to many, many training courses, both internal and external to Google (and at previous jobs). I’ve also designed conferences of various sizes (everything from 7-person team forming/development style things, to 200-person multi-day offsites). These were mostly for engineers, who seem to have a higher population of introverts than is normal (in the statistical sense). For many of these, I’ve had the opportunity to structure agendas and content so it’s a conference I’d like to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have opinions and a text editor, so get comfy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why in-person Gatherings are a Good Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summits are great, right? Yay summits. We’re going to have a summit. Or we’re going to do a training course or a team-building event. Won’t it be jolly? We’re going to have the best of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Team Cohesion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘full mesh’ of a team interacting at a personal level isn’t something you can replicate with any level of technology. You can install 4K resolution videoconference units on every flat surface in the office, but it still doesn’t beat having a large, high-bandwidth conversation in person. Maybe you, as the conference organiser, have a big announcement or a big program to charter. Maybe there’s a discrete thing to get done. Great, these are good when they can be done in person. Picking up on nuances of what people think is way easier in person. You don’t get the 5 minutes of unfiltered chat on one side, after the conference call shuts down - it’s all in the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accidental Collaboration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is a team meeting, you often get sidebar conversations that happen outside the core agenda. A lot of good stuff happens here. Ask yourself this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your conference had no agenda, and you just put the people in a large space with the tools to work together, would it have been a useful time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, this is a useful cohort. This is a good use of everyone’s time and you’re already winning just by having this cohort spend time together. Any agenda on top is gravy. Pat yourself on the back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Personal Connections&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if someone doesn’t share much about their life outside work, it’s good to ‘reset the clock’ and get some face time anyway. It can be hard to maintain an interpersonal relationship when all your interactions (i.e. meetings) are preambled with an implicit “We’re going to have this necessary conversation and then we’ll go do other things”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 6-9 months of no unnecessary social contact, a person stops being a person and starts being email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true. I’ve been on both ends of the equation. You start to mischaracterise people, to question motives, and to ‘debug’ them when they do something you might see as unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why in-person conferences are tiresome and costly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess append “If not chartered or run properly”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assuming Full Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This especially applies to introverts - since time is usually at a premium, there’s the temptation to cram as much content in as possible. 9am starts, working lunches, late finishes, pre-arranged dinner, drinks, etc. It isn’t that half of us are secretly suffering inexorable internal torture or anything - it’s just really, really tiring and takes it out of you. If you’re combining that with expecting top quality &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GyV_UG60dD4"&gt;synergies&lt;/a&gt; from people, it’s not always going to end well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Getting the Content right is hard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to stay engaged if the content isn’t interesting or engaging. If things are in the wrong order, or the pacing is off, or it isn’t presented engagingly, it can end up being a place people don’t want to be. Obviously the art and science of running good meetings is an entire career unto itself, but try to get it right-ish, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Formal Persona&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings are pretty easy. They’re usually short, and for a particular purpose. It is pretty easy to have a conversation about a thing, end that conversation, and move on. When you put the same people into a much less formal situation, where they have to keep their ‘game face’ on for hours or days at a time, it can be emotionally jarring. Remember, people usually have the means to escape, mull over what’s happened, absorb, and respond. You’re removing that option for them, at least for this event. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making things Bearable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s where it gets specific. Remember, this is what has worked for me when organising, and what I’ve really appreciated when attending. YMMV, and this is by no means a complete list for all introverts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overarching goal for the preparation part is to allow people to build a mental picture of what the gathering is going to look like - who’ll be there, what will generally be discussed, what the format is, what degree of participation is needed from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Preparation and Planning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Have a Charter Document&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Be forthright as to why this meeting is a good idea. Publish what you want to get done. Remember, this is a sales job as much as anything. Make it compelling.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Have sounding boards for your agenda and plans&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Obviously these should be people who are prepared to tell you you’re full of it (if you are).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;It might be a good idea to invite a ‘conference skeptic’ to comment (we’ve all got one).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Allow people to build their own mental picture of what the summit might be like.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Publish a schedule as early as humanly possible.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Even if it’s incomplete, or has “Insert external speaker here” placeholders.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Getting used to the ideas inside, building a mental picture, and mentally preparing is super important.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Arrange to record talks if you can, and share content afterwards&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Even though people being there is important, it should not be essential absolutely all of the time&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON'T&lt;/b&gt;: Generate ‘buzz’ by keeping important things secret.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“We have a special secret ice-breaker planned for the wednesday evening, it’s going to be super fun!”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Haha. How about no. Things that make you interact with strangers in surprising ways are to be avoided.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;It’s OK to have surprises (Schwag, special appearances, etc.), once it’s a passive event from the cohort’s point of view.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Determining the Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Make sure there’s enough time for each item.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be generous with time, make sure you’re able to cover everything.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Schedule breaks generously.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Long enough that people can actually escape.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Think about the flow of the agenda.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Is it all super-serious decision-making all the time? Could we break it up a bit?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Consider the expected energy in the room.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Do we want to make all our decisions in the morning? The afternoon?
    &lt;li&gt;Are decisions made at 4:30pm after a full day good quality decisions?
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON’T&lt;/b&gt;: Assume ‘breakout groups’ are a break from the larger conference.
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;They’re often more stressful, as they force interaction with strangers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON’T&lt;/b&gt;: Assume anything about breakfast, lunch, or evenings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lunch is an hour to escape the cohort. Let people do it.
    &lt;li&gt;Yes, I’ve had ‘tasks’ set with a small group of people I’d met that day, that I was supposed to do with them over lunch.
    &lt;li&gt;I’ve also had ‘expected’ pre-arranged dinner and drinks attendance. Please don’t do this.
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON’T&lt;/b&gt;: Plan ‘ice-breakers’ that require divulging personal information.
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;People should not feel pressured into sharing anything they don’t feel like sharing. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Yes, this might include things you think are innocuous.
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Read the Room!
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If the energy level is dropping, have a break. Even an unscheduled one.
    &lt;li&gt;If a conversation is going nowhere, watch for people disengaging. Move on or reset.
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DO&lt;/b&gt;: Offer disengagement as an option
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If someone wants to bow out, let them actively disengage (i.e. leave).
    &lt;li&gt;They should respect the process by letting you know (afterwards) their reasons.
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON’T&lt;/b&gt;: Skimp on break times.
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breaks should be 15 minutes, at least. Enough time to go for a short walk, sit somewhere quiet, do a quick email check. Even longer if there are logistical things (bathrooms are far away or not plentiful (especially if your conference is gender-skewed), local cafe is busy, singleton coffee machine, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;DON’T&lt;/b&gt;: Try to include everyone equally
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Some people are talkers, some listeners and chimers-in.
    &lt;li&gt;While you want to make sure everyone has the opportunity to collaborate and participate, try to strike a balance between letting the talkers talk, and giving quieter people an opening.
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Making things Excellent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the above might seem like introverts should be coddled, or need special treatment. This isn’t especially the case -- as noted before, we’re talking about half of all people, here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conferences should push people, to an extent. In many cases, you may be introducing people to concepts and conversations that challenge them. There should be a certain amount of discomfort, without it being enough that someone chooses to revert and disengage. This is difficult to get right -- hopefully some of the above tips will get you a lot of the way there. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Writing"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="conferences"></category><category term="introverts"></category></entry><entry><title>June 12 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/june-12-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-12T12:04:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-12T12:04:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-06-12:/june-12-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160612-nespresso.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160612-nespresso.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was away last week with work to an offsite at the &lt;a href="https://www.clubmed.co.uk/r/Opio-en-Provence/y"&gt;Club Med&lt;/a&gt;, which as far as I can 
gather is one of those soviet-era collective holiday camps for people who weren't in a soviet. I bet the soviets never
had nespresso on demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bizarrely, the weather in Ireland …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160612-nespresso.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160612-nespresso.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was away last week with work to an offsite at the &lt;a href="https://www.clubmed.co.uk/r/Opio-en-Provence/y"&gt;Club Med&lt;/a&gt;, which as far as I can 
gather is one of those soviet-era collective holiday camps for people who weren't in a soviet. I bet the soviets never
had nespresso on demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bizarrely, the weather in Ireland was actually better than in the south of France. No complaints though :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, the weather at home is fighting with itself -- sunshine and high (for Ireland) temperatures, with "showers" that range
in intensity from light drizzle to attempted murder. Will still try to bike it to work as I can this week. Actually the first
full week in many weeks, so trying to git 'er done moreso than I have been.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>June 05 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/june-05-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-06-05T19:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-06-05T19:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-06-05:/june-05-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160605-rhubarb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160605-rhubarb.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather turns and turns. We're well into the season where things spring out, and make you cut them back,
or just be happy they're there. Our garden has rhubarb. Enough for a tiny put of jam, or perhaps
a Mr. Kipling's style rhubarb tartlet or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160605-rhubarb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160605-rhubarb.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather turns and turns. We're well into the season where things spring out, and make you cut them back,
or just be happy they're there. Our garden has rhubarb. Enough for a tiny put of jam, or perhaps
a Mr. Kipling's style rhubarb tartlet or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also is the season for camping, weekend activities that involve outside, and being on the motorbike a
lot more. I was away for much of last week, looking forward to more of the outside, assuming the last 
week or so wasn't a trick.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>May 25 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/may-25-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-25T13:05:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-25T13:05:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-05-25:/may-25-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160525-theguy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160525-theguy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further to the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/1w1y5m/we_are_the_google_site_reliability_engineering/cexy5sd"&gt;Reddit AMA&lt;/a&gt; I was
involved in a few years back (I am /u/sre_pointyhair) - "The Guy" showed up at my desk last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, I was away, and he had to make do with doing the unspeakable things we do to keep servers running from my desk …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160525-theguy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160525-theguy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further to the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/1w1y5m/we_are_the_google_site_reliability_engineering/cexy5sd"&gt;Reddit AMA&lt;/a&gt; I was
involved in a few years back (I am /u/sre_pointyhair) - "The Guy" showed up at my desk last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, I was away, and he had to make do with doing the unspeakable things we do to keep servers running from my desk for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, nothing exploded.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>Imperfect Machines</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/imperfect-machines.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-19T23:33:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-05-19T23:33:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-05-19:/imperfect-machines.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160519-book.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160519-book.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got my grubby mitts on an actual dead-tree copy of the SRE book. I've wanted this to exist
for many years, and it's finally out there. I wrote a chapter on working with teams with high interrupt loads
where the team consists of humans. It's a paraphrase of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160519-book.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160519-book.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got my grubby mitts on an actual dead-tree copy of the SRE book. I've wanted this to exist
for many years, and it's finally out there. I wrote a chapter on working with teams with high interrupt loads
where the team consists of humans. It's a paraphrase of a paper I wrote a few years back that's used internally
across a few teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much as we all need to get grunge work done, often the 'fair' way to divide it is unfair to everyone individually. 
People work best where they get to do one thing well for as long an uninterrupted session of time as possible. It's a
concept that I get pushed back on quite a bit, as it's dangerously close to claiming human can't multitask, and people 
love to claim they can. But, it's a pretty simple concept that's worked well where applied. Polarise time, sanity may well follow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>April 30 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/april-30-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-30T19:14:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-30T19:14:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-04-30:/april-30-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160430-pewpewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160430-pewpewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back from a few days in Prague and beyond, at &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz/"&gt;Border War&lt;/a&gt;. This was a very decent one - and
I ended up not being as wrecked as I thought (due to the previously mentioned unfitness). Did about 45km of hiking over the 
3 days of the event, which is a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160430-pewpewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160430-pewpewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back from a few days in Prague and beyond, at &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz/"&gt;Border War&lt;/a&gt;. This was a very decent one - and
I ended up not being as wrecked as I thought (due to the previously mentioned unfitness). Did about 45km of hiking over the 
3 days of the event, which is a lot for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This (as usual) has sparked plans for more trips. Work has been busy (in a good way) for a while, so plans for non-work are 
spinning up, which I guess is the real sign of spring (I've got things I could be doing for about half the weekends until July already).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More of this sort of thing, plz.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="airsoft"></category></entry><entry><title>The Technical Contrarian</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/the-technical-contrarian.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-16T22:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-16T22:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-04-16:/the-technical-contrarian.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, case in point (since we love examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, when I first started fiddling with &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first 
things in the docs was 'okay, set up virtualenv and do such a thing'. My initial reaction, as an old-skool sysadmin weenie who hasn't 
had to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, case in point (since we love examples).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, when I first started fiddling with &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, one of the first 
things in the docs was 'okay, set up virtualenv and do such a thing'. My initial reaction, as an old-skool sysadmin weenie who hasn't 
had to actually run a linux install that I care about in many years, was to go 'pfft', and just get python going on the machine 
I wanted to use pelican on (i.e. my macbook). This, of course, resulted in a world of hurt, as the first thing you do is pick between pip and easy_install, and your first step being to pick a package manager is never a good sign (I've used python for years, so I'm kinda familiar with its vagaries, but y'know. All the same.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, step one for me was to run into virtualenv, declare it to be newfangled, and do what I know. I don't feel like I'm a person who rejects things out of hand for being newfangled all on their own. However, that was my initial instinct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I decided I'd do a bit more writing a few weeks back, I threw ludditism to the wind, and said "OK, let's use virtualenv'. &lt;strong&gt;I was up and running in less than 5 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;. Now I have a (kind of, I assume) idempotent virtual environment for python sitting in dropbox, that I assume will work on other OSX installs. Or maybe elsewhere. Have yet to test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the point is, it was quick, painless, and I probably could have done the same thing a few years ago and saved a bunch of hassle. But I didn't -- and I'm interested in why. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may, of course, go back to one of the truisms I like to come out with, which is &lt;em&gt;People enjoy things they remember&lt;/em&gt;. I remember how to install stuff from source, how &lt;strong&gt;./configure &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make install&lt;/strong&gt; was the old &lt;strong&gt;curl blah | bash&lt;/strong&gt;, and even though the logical brain knows that the thing that's had thousands of hours of work, and tens of thousands of hours of nerd scrutiny applied to it, and is &lt;em&gt;what the software maintainer recommends&lt;/em&gt; will probably work, and may surprise you, you're still gonna go "Install packages? Yeah, I've done that. I'll take it from here, documentation". It's like following the first half of the IKEA instructions and then reckoning you can wing it from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing like new ways of doing things to make you feel a bit left behind, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it's hard to see what's actually a good way of doing things, and what's generally a bad idea. This varies by your risk aversion, and how bothered you are, and how much you like/trust/care for the community behind this stuff. You used to be able to get a good feel for what's a decent idea as far as sysadmin goes. Now it seems more like you have to be careful about picking your poison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other case in point! -- Docker Hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been playing a bit with &lt;a href="http://www.docker.com"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; for a while, and I've been happy enough with how it functions so far. I haven't in any way stressed it as far as functionality goes (mainly I've been using it at home for Plex, Sonarr, SabNZBd, for, uh, reasons). However, one of the first things you get exposed to is docker hub -- which is basically a giant Makefile repository for docker images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gives me the fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know why it gives me the fear in a more substantial way than, say, &lt;em&gt;running any software&lt;/em&gt;, but I'm still kinda finding it hard in my brain to distinguish it from the &lt;strong&gt;sudo | bash&lt;/strong&gt; school of package management, in terms of trusting your machine to a random thing from internet strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, we run software written by strangers all the time, right? There's no 'score' assigned to any of this software like docker images from docker hub, right? I've spent long enough reading occasional stories about how some prominent OSS people are deranged maniacs to know that the scrutiny leveled at, say, the sabnzbd or sonarr software itself is far less than the &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/timhaak/plex/"&gt;111 stars and 100k+ pulls&lt;/a&gt; that the highest-rated plex Dockerfile has. Hell, Plex is closed source so who knows what it's doing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might trust the crowd. That's fine, too. It might result in just as simple a life as only trusting yourself, all things considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it comes back to one of the key interests I have, that I've yet to tease out into an 'area of study', really -- the effect of human instinct, emotion and judgement on how we go about interacting with software, especially software we rely on to stay working. People mistake 'correct' for 'safe' or 'familiar' or 'comfortable' all the time, and there's very little acknowledgement of the basic emotions at play. People imagine it as a very dry, scientific discipline -- but some of the most strident arguments I've encountered have been over two perfectly fine methods, software elements, processes, or whatever you run into when dealing with these ridiculous computer contraptions we deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you think vi is better than emacs because you have muscle memory, or because your girlfriend tought you to use it and that's a happy memory, or you personally have it set up just-so, and it's a classic nerd-brain trope to imagine everyone is just like you, because things are simpler that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe vi's better than emacs because it just is and I'm tired of this argument, so shut your damn hell mouth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meta"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="writing"></category><category term="brains"></category></entry><entry><title>Border War Prep 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/border-war-prep-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-16T21:54:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-16T21:54:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-04-16:/border-war-prep-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160416-gear.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160416-gear.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the gear that's being shipped to Czech Republic (or &lt;a href="http://www.go-czechia.com/"&gt;Czechia&lt;/a&gt; if you don't please) for &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz/"&gt;Border War&lt;/a&gt; next week. I and 20-odd other tubby nerd militia follow it all next week. This will be my third time in as many years, and probably the unfittest I've been in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20160416-gear.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20160416-gear.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the gear that's being shipped to Czech Republic (or &lt;a href="http://www.go-czechia.com/"&gt;Czechia&lt;/a&gt; if you don't please) for &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz/"&gt;Border War&lt;/a&gt; next week. I and 20-odd other tubby nerd militia follow it all next week. This will be my third time in as many years, and probably the unfittest I've been in about that time. Let's see if I manage to hold my own or expire (It's 3 days of camping and about 30-40km of hiking with a load of gear on you).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, the weather looks to be clearing up and staying cleared up, which means a bunch of motorbike commuting (and gadding about). This is a good thing for the brains.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="airsoft"></category><category term="fitness"></category></entry><entry><title>April 11 2016</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/april-11-2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-04-11T00:42:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-04-11T00:42:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2016-04-11:/april-11-2016.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I almost signed up for a medium account. A brief moment of madness before I realised that
the likes of medium accounts are also transient. Reminded, again, by my recent de-facto abandonment of G+ 
as a thing to publish things on. I am not a crackpot, our outlets for writing …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I almost signed up for a medium account. A brief moment of madness before I realised that
the likes of medium accounts are also transient. Reminded, again, by my recent de-facto abandonment of G+ 
as a thing to publish things on. I am not a crackpot, our outlets for writing are transient and we're 
in danger of not having a narrative at all if (some of us) don't self-curate :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In since-last-year news, things are progressing, for certain values of progress. As far as the Internet at large is concerned,
 I now have about twice as many people who have the good|bad|indifferent fortune of being in my organisation at work (I know,
"my organisation", right?). Things have gotten really busy since about the start of this year, but in a good way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is my solemn belief that the average person should know how to do about 90% of their job. Thereabouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wrote a chapter for the &lt;a href="http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920041528.do"&gt;SRE Book&lt;/a&gt;. Not on anything technical
of course. On manager-nerd stuff. A dabbler in code and people. It was a paper I'd had sitting internally for a while, that 
is now seeing the light of day, in edited form. I am glad this book exists, as I have honestly believed that what we're doing is
capital-I Important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also get on. I get on okay. How are you?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="sre"></category><category term="writing"></category></entry><entry><title>February 17 2015</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/february-17-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-02-17T20:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-02-17T20:59:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2015-02-17:/february-17-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150217-newbike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150217-newbike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather's turning. It's one of those nice times of year when it's cold and mostly dry, but without a winter in front of us. Things are growing at home and we're seeing what pops up on our first spring in the new place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on Valentine's day, I reminded …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150217-newbike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150217-newbike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather's turning. It's one of those nice times of year when it's cold and mostly dry, but without a winter in front of us. Things are growing at home and we're seeing what pops up on our first spring in the new place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, on Valentine's day, I reminded myself of how much I love myself, and got a new motorbike. It's the little things. Love you lots babe xoxo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently in London, doing a short trip for work. Have managed only short trips so far (to Zurich, and now here) -- I've a few longer trips coming up, but they should be mostly uneventful. I don't have the appetite for long trips any more, to anywhere. There's too much at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the weather gets nicer, I also mean to get fitter (i.e. fitter than not fit at all). The house buying moved us further out from work, and introduced stress that means I've been off the self-powered bike for a while. I've a pretty big &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz"&gt;Airsoft Event&lt;/a&gt; coming up in April, and not dropping dead from running for a few hundred metres would be just great. I'm funny with exercise in that I can't stick to it unless it has a point. So, bike commuting was great. Gym, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I say this after inhaling a &lt;a href="http://www.fortyburgers.co.uk/"&gt;Pretty Nice Burger&lt;/a&gt; in a local place here. Whoops-a-daisy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="motorcycle"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>January 11 2015</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/january-11-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-11T15:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-01-11T15:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2015-01-11:/january-11-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150111-windits.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150111-windits.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic weekend! The first week back at work was one of those stealth first-weeks-back, where the first part is relief that nothing exploded in my 3 weeks away, and the rest was EVERYTHING HAPPENING. But it's the weekend now, and Amazon has a fancy Karcher window vacuum on sale. A …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150111-windits.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150111-windits.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic weekend! The first week back at work was one of those stealth first-weeks-back, where the first part is relief that nothing exploded in my 3 weeks away, and the rest was EVERYTHING HAPPENING. But it's the weekend now, and Amazon has a fancy Karcher window vacuum on sale. A window vacuum, if you don't mind. It actually worked, which restored my faith in branding (I wouldn't have bothered with one and would have declared them bullshit if Karcher hadn't been making one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somoene mentioned &lt;a href="http://www.medium.com/"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; to me last week, as a means to 'tweet a thing with more words than a tweet'. Over the years, I've used a bunch of things to keep an accessible log. I used to use &lt;a href="http://www.livejournal.com/"&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt; until some russian mobsters bought it. I used to keep up with people on some NNTP groups, or via email. I don't really do email with people any more, which is a shame in a sort of compresed-time way. Remember when we used to write letters? I don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I'm pretty sure that some HTML files in a directory aren't going to get deprecated or fall out of favour any time soon. I can carry a means to reproduce them anywhere with me, I can rejigger them to some other format if the world moves on, I can use some other form of syndication, because I have the originals in markdown. You could argue that it won't fall out of favour because it isn't in favour, and you'd be right :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes think about how temporary a lot of social media is. People from the older school of personal journaling or websites came into it with an expectation that it'd be a record of their travels through life. It really hasn't become that, and I think that's fine - it is what it defines itself to be, which is a moving set of goalposts. Will Facebook be around in 40+ years, when I hope to be still here? I don't know, and neither do you. Will it offer a means to search for the times I talked about a particular thing at any point in the past? It doesn't even do that now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, just in the interests of fairness, neither do G+ or twitter in any meaninfgul way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, all this is a huge distraction from how I need to clean my kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="facebook"></category><category term="logging"></category><category term="domestic"></category><category term="weekend"></category></entry><entry><title>January 01 2015</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/january-01-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-01T02:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-01-01T02:05:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2015-01-01:/january-01-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150101-desk.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150101-desk.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, every October or so, I ask HR at work for a report of people on my team (I have somehow tricked The Company, or they have tricked me, into being responsible for about 40 people) who haven't taken enough vacation, since we can only carry over 5 days. Due …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20150101-desk.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20150101-desk.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, every October or so, I ask HR at work for a report of people on my team (I have somehow tricked The Company, or they have tricked me, into being responsible for about 40 people) who haven't taken enough vacation, since we can only carry over 5 days. Due to accounting messing about for my leave earlier this year, It turns out I had 17 days left, and could only carry over 5. "Whoops", I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I took 3 weeks off. My leave in the summer was good, and overdue, but stressful and punctuated by having to call people, stand over people as they do jobs, worry about things going well (Ever had to hope a plumber has a steady hand drilling a hole in a 500 euro ceramic sink, as you race to a kitchen suppliers to get parts they forgot to send out and you needed today? That was a fun tuesday morning). A lot of it felt a lot more like work than I would have liked. So, this time round, I made a small list of "Things I will feel like a failure as a person for not getting done". I then promptly did about half of them, then declared "Fuck it, it's Christmas" and sat around enjoying the outcome of the previous time spent working. It has been glorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 has been one of the more eventful years in the last few. Of course, I moved house, for the first time in almost 10 years. The above picture is my workbench for doing electronics messing and airsoft, which only got unpacked and set up this week. This will give you an idea of my approach to moving. I still have a roomful of boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also did more of my "Doing things is better than not doing things" stuff. For me, as an on-again off-again &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalized_anxiety_disorder"&gt;GAD&lt;/a&gt; sufferer, this has brought about an amazing sense of well-being. The alternative to figuring out how to be alive like this is the slow death of coasting through life without ever challenging yourself. I'm doing it in small way. I'm not about to take up lion-taming, but I'm doing my bit. I did the mandatory training and started riding a motorcycle, which was a big unnecessary thing I thought would help, and it has. It's easy (and especially easy for me) to rationalise away any thoughts of doing things that aren't strictly necessary - it's a defence mechanism against failure. I'm trying my best to do things when my brain goes "Bleh". I'm also trying my best to fulfil a few of the "Wouldn't it be cool if..." ideas I often have and then squirrel away for 'later'. There's no later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopes for 2015? I'm trying hard to have specific ones. It's not something I think about a lot, and the 'five year plans are for losers' attitude that got me through my 20s has worn thin a little bit. So, I'm still thinking about it. I hope I can do more stuff that I've only thought of doing but then threw away the idea before. I hope I can figure out a reproducible way of making myself happy. I hope I can be a better partner, a better manager, and a more open person without stressing myself out or being uncomfortable all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts with doing things. Because that is, after all, better than not doing things.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>December 07 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/december-07-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-07T13:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-12-07T13:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-12-07:/december-07-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141207-goodjob.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141207-goodjob.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of this year's travel is ongoing. I haven't had a weekend in NYC in a while, and it's managed not to snow this time. A decent day yesterday walking around the park and times square in the rain, and visiting &lt;a href="http://www.moma.org/"&gt;MoMA&lt;/a&gt; for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is more …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141207-goodjob.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141207-goodjob.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of this year's travel is ongoing. I haven't had a weekend in NYC in a while, and it's managed not to snow this time. A decent day yesterday walking around the park and times square in the rain, and visiting &lt;a href="http://www.moma.org/"&gt;MoMA&lt;/a&gt; for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is more synergy - a meeting of managers from all over to talk about The Company's storage, the teams that run it, and various other bits. It's the stuff I'm interested enough in that it doesn't feel like work. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here until thursday or so, the heading home to a bunch of time off for xmas and new years. I've alwys taken the two weeks surrounding xmas and new year's off, for my entire working life. Of course, this means that the week before the week before xmas always ends up being an exercise in clock-watching (yes, even if I do like my job. It's not quite at the level of 'xmas every day' just yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this year, I took that week off as well. I'm sure nothing bad can come of this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>November 12 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/november-12-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-12T22:15:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-12T22:15:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-11-12:/november-12-2014.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141112-cats.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141112-cats.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home again, at least until next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You'd almost think they missed me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>November 4 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/november-4-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-04T22:02:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-04T22:02:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-11-04:/november-4-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141104-bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141104-bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent korean BBQ is a lot less cheaty than sausage and stodge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hoped, got a bunch of stuff done on the plane, and managed to not have an awful flight. I can tell my sinuses aren't going to like it later, but for the moment I can take solace …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141104-bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141104-bbq.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent korean BBQ is a lot less cheaty than sausage and stodge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As hoped, got a bunch of stuff done on the plane, and managed to not have an awful flight. I can tell my sinuses aren't going to like it later, but for the moment I can take solace in meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mountain View is as it usually is, except it feels a lot more like it's reached its tipping point as far as straining the local infrastructure goes. People don't want to live near the office (because let's face it, Mountain View itself is a bit of a shithole), so they end up commuting &amp;gt;1h from San Francisco (which is also a shithole) every day. At some point, being in the centre of the universe gets outweighed by a declining quality of life. Hopefully something creative happens, since I don't think it's a problem unique to The Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more day in the office, then hitting the red-eye to NYC tomorrow night. I expect that to be a less pleasant flight, but at least I'll then be in NYC.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>November 1 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/november-1-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-01T21:43:00+00:00</published><updated>2014-11-01T21:43:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-11-01:/november-1-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141101-travelgear.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141101-travelgear.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off to Mountain View in the morning for 3 days, then onwards to New York. I haven't been to MTV since January, or NYC since June, so I guess I'm due in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the aeroplane survival kit. I don't sleep on planes, and Aer Lingus have transatlantic WiFi …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141101-travelgear.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141101-travelgear.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off to Mountain View in the morning for 3 days, then onwards to New York. I haven't been to MTV since January, or NYC since June, so I guess I'm due in both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the aeroplane survival kit. I don't sleep on planes, and Aer Lingus have transatlantic WiFi now, so this is indispensble. That's the work phone (Nexus 4), work tablet (Nexus 10), and the newly-acquired Moto 360 smartwatch, which the jury is still out on (pretty shiny so far though).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three other pieces of indisensible kit are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/15000mAh-Portable-External-Battery-Motorola-Black/dp/B00D5T3QK4/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1415828791&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=anker+astro"&gt;Anker ASTRO E5&lt;/a&gt; battery pack for charging hungry gadgets on the road.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Family-Sized-Desktop-Charger-Technology-External/dp/B00GYNW1TA/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1415828825&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=anker+usb"&gt;Anker&lt;/a&gt; 5-way USB charging thingo (2.4A on each of 5 ports for maximum charging goodness)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/WL-330NUL-All-In-One-Wireless-N-Pocket-Router/dp/B00CYI46MO/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1415828976&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=asus+wl-330nul"&gt;ASUS WL-330NUL&lt;/a&gt; USB ethernet and mobile hotspot, for sharing stupid one-mac-address wifi with all your gadgets (seriously, everyone should have one of these).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I'll get some stuff done on the plane - I've yet to properly emulate the distraction-deprivation environment that planes give you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeya on the other side, internet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>October 21 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/october-21-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-21T21:36:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-21T21:36:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-10-21:/october-21-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141021-munichmenu.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141021-munichmenu.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a work conference in Munich, which I've never been to before. From what I have seen of restaurants here, it is a Paleo disaster, so I've been pretty cheat-y so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As middle-european cities go, it's pretty nice -- ageing but efficient train service, pants-shitting taxi rides from the airport …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141021-munichmenu.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141021-munichmenu.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a work conference in Munich, which I've never been to before. From what I have seen of restaurants here, it is a Paleo disaster, so I've been pretty cheat-y so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As middle-european cities go, it's pretty nice -- ageing but efficient train service, pants-shitting taxi rides from the airport at 220kph, and good food and company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get to spend essentially no free time here, but maybe I'll come back sometime. For now, I get to go back home for a week, then do a short-in-duration but long-in-distance jaunt. The joy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="munich"></category></entry><entry><title>October 18 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/october-18-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-18T14:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-18T14:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-10-18:/october-18-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141018-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141018-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More inactivity! Mainly it's been ridiculously busy in work, mostly around performance reviews and a number of things sneaking up on me. They're sneaky, those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing a little more travel before the end of the year -- Munich, London, Mountain View and New York (twice). Yay. I've been very travel-light …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141018-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141018-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More inactivity! Mainly it's been ridiculously busy in work, mostly around performance reviews and a number of things sneaking up on me. They're sneaky, those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing a little more travel before the end of the year -- Munich, London, Mountain View and New York (twice). Yay. I've been very travel-light this year, so I guess I gots to pay my dues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I own a motorbike now! It's a 2004 Honda NT650V Deauville. It'll do for now - I meanly needed a bigger bike after I discovered that the 250cc bike I was on was hardly pulling me, and I found it way, way easier to ride the school bike (an SV650S). Of course, I'd pick a day with gale-force winds to pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also booked my test, on advice of the instructor - I did an insurance assessment and was given a grade equivalent to 'has a full license and is a daily rider'. Which had the nice side-effect of 30% off my insurance. Let's hope I can keep that up when I don't have a dude following me and roaring at me over a radio.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="motorbike"></category></entry><entry><title>October 05 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/october-05-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-05T11:51:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-10-05T11:51:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-10-05:/october-05-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141005-steak.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141005-steak.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to keep this thing up by doing worthwhile things. That was the idea, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying &lt;a href="http://thepaleodiet.com/"&gt;Paleo&lt;/a&gt; for the last few weeks, with a drop of about 1.1kg per week so far. Seems normal enough for exercise free diet change (from previous experience), and it's a bit …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20141005-steak.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20141005-steak.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to keep this thing up by doing worthwhile things. That was the idea, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying &lt;a href="http://thepaleodiet.com/"&gt;Paleo&lt;/a&gt; for the last few weeks, with a drop of about 1.1kg per week so far. Seems normal enough for exercise free diet change (from previous experience), and it's a bit easier on the palate than just caloric reduction or other stuff - we'll see how long it lasts. I've noticed a bit more energy certainly, and less feeling bloated and horrible. The first couple of weeks off work really took it out of me, and the brain can't really perform if the body isn't keeping up. It's too far out to be cycling to work any more, so diet will have to come first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motorbike stuff is still in the pant-shitting terror mode for a lot of it, which I hear is quite normal and healthy. I know I see it in the car as well, but inconsiderate arseholes are legion on Irish roads - people should have to spend some time on a bike or motorbike to understand this. On the other hand, we've had some great weather the last few weeks, and I'm enjoying the hell out of the long straight bits. Back in this week for some more refresher lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have also solidified travel for the next while - going to Munich, London, Mountain View and NYC before the end of the year; in short trips for the most part. Also, got a ticket for &lt;a href="http://www.borderwar.cz/"&gt;Border War&lt;/a&gt; next year - I'm so there I'm not even here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="motorbike"></category></entry><entry><title>September 16th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/september-16th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-16T14:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-09-16T14:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-09-16:/september-16th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140916-zurich.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140916-zurich.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Away in Zurich for a few days with work. Partially to meet a bunch of people, but also to get into the practice of being away from home in small doses. I've a few more trips coming up (London, Munich, etc) that'll also help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been dealing with a bit …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140916-zurich.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Image" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140916-zurich.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Away in Zurich for a few days with work. Partially to meet a bunch of people, but also to get into the practice of being away from home in small doses. I've a few more trips coming up (London, Munich, etc) that'll also help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been dealing with a bit of low-level anxiety about leaving the house empty - it's a good bit more secluded than the old place, which means I don't like leaving it alone. For this and a few future trips, I have someone going in there pretty much every day (or living there), but I just have to deal with it -- Alarm systems, CCTV, home automation only go so far. If stuff happens, it happens. Bizarrely, in my head it's the cats I'd be more worried about. Stuff is just stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Zurich in June, but didn't get to see any of it -- so I'm getting around this time by walking. I really like old european cities, where people actually use the space. It's one of the things I don't like about Dublin -- people don't look like they're using the space and kind of scurry around between Things They Gotta Do. Hard to explain. What I have learned is that I need a comfortable pair of walking shoes, and to become less of a fat sack of shit (I stopped getting any regular exercise right when I bought the new house and stress took over. Need to reverse that trend.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to do some gaming over the weekend at &lt;a href="http://iga.ie/heckcon/"&gt;Heckcon&lt;/a&gt;, which was nice - I've been trying to do a little more of this, since it was one of the things I consciously enjoyed that I just petered out with doing. I'm getting set up for &lt;a href="http://www.gaelcon.com/"&gt;Gaelcon&lt;/a&gt; in a month or so, and may even run a game. There's also a set of people that I only really run into at cons, and it'll be good to get kept up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="gaming"></category></entry><entry><title>September 12th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/september-12th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-12T21:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-09-12T21:11:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-09-12:/september-12th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140912-windscreen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Whoops!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140912-windscreen.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second week back, and seeing what my job ends up looking like for the next while. Think 'busy'. I'm trying to nail down travel until the end of the year, it being increasingly impossible. I'll be in Zurich for a while next week, and after that is anyone's guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140912-windscreen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Whoops!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140912-windscreen.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second week back, and seeing what my job ends up looking like for the next while. Think 'busy'. I'm trying to nail down travel until the end of the year, it being increasingly impossible. I'll be in Zurich for a while next week, and after that is anyone's guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other delightful happenings: Someone working on another building in the campus our building is in managed to reverse a van into the motorbike. The only real damage was to the airblade windscreen, which got broken pretty much clean in half (see picture). After removing the remains, I discovered that all it was really doing was redirecting wind into my face, and riding the bike got a bit nicer to do. So, thanks clumsy van driver I guess.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="motorbike"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>September 7th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/september-7th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-09-07T21:11:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-09-07T21:11:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-09-07:/september-7th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140907-pewhat.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Yup" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140907-pewhat.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First week back at work - done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things have been more physically tiring than otherwise. I've been trying to nail down the next couple of months travel wise, and managed to make it into work on the bike 
two days out of five, which was good. That's been helped along by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140907-pewhat.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Yup" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140907-pewhat.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First week back at work - done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things have been more physically tiring than otherwise. I've been trying to nail down the next couple of months travel wise, and managed to make it into work on the bike 
two days out of five, which was good. That's been helped along by some good weather, and unhelped by some &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_cR988dih2s&amp;amp;list=UU9mvpPZi6qU_Bc9kxU0pYAw"&gt;impatient drivers&lt;/a&gt; (that get caught on my helmet cam and youtubed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend saw some Airsoft, and some moving of larger items from the old house. It's not quite the insuroutable chore I've assumed it would be any more, a couple more trips will do it, I think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="brain"></category></entry><entry><title>August 31st 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-31st-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-31T21:30:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-31T21:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-31:/august-31st-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140831-gimme.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gimme!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140831-gimme.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day of leave, and a day of normalcy and domesticity. Mainly hung around and enjoyed the last of the days since the end of June, when I last went near work. Tomorrow will see some hectic times, when I figure out what's happened while I've been away. If I've …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140831-gimme.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gimme!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140831-gimme.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day of leave, and a day of normalcy and domesticity. Mainly hung around and enjoyed the last of the days since the end of June, when I last went near work. Tomorrow will see some hectic times, when I figure out what's happened while I've been away. If I've been doing it right, very little! The best work disappears, as they say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These few months off have given me a bit of time to think about larger things -- I've gotten a lot of stuff done, and have thought about a lot more stuff. My brain has not been terribly healthy these last few years, and part of what I hoped to figure out was what I might end up doing (or not doing) to make it be a little healtier. I had a couple of bad signs, like mood swings that weren't linked to any external stimuli, that mean I may end up seeing a professional again at some point. However, on other fronts things are a lot better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, I've finally acknowledged that I'm actually not made happy by being lazy. The last proper frame of reference I had with enough time to introspect on it was college and soon after, where I could do stuff like spend a week playing Baldur's Gate, or similar goofing off. I often stressed myself out in recent years because I don't seem to get the time to do that sort of thing any more. However, given the opportunity to do so, I found myself not really able for it - the thought of not doing something productive, or not doing something at least worthwhile outweighed the stress for not being able to goof off (if that makes sense). So tl;dr: The marathon laziness sessions I get stressed about not doing are actually bad for me when I get to do them. I don't like them. The reason in my head, at least, seems to be that the part of my brain that wants things is a bit disconnected from the part that enjoys experiences and feeds back. It also probably means that I did some growing as a person without really noticing. So, I got to rationalise away a source of stress :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For another: this leave almost acted as a catalyst for realising what I'm going to do, ever, and what I'm not going to do. For a long time, I've had in the back of my brain "Someday I'll do X", where X is a thing that's completely possible for me to do now. Someday I'll go travel in a particular place. Someday I'll learn a particular skill. It'll happen in the empty space that I can retionalise away as "When I have time off work". I just had time off work, and only got one or two of these things done (the motorcycle thing, and some other social things I may go into later). Now that I'm back at work, I realise: there is no later. Unless you're prepared to make a long list and wait for retirement (and hope you make it in one piece and are able-bodied enough to tick them off) you're just not going to do these things. You sweep them away forward into a fold in time, which usually means 'never'. So, if I find myself going "I'd like to do X sometime when I've time", the time is now. Or soon. Make plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been extraordinarily lucky in my work life - I have a job I love doing, that pays well and is flexible about lifestyle. I have a Significant Other that is the world to me, and that I want to share my life with if I can. I have most of my life left to make of it what I can. The last thing I need is self-denial and some-other-time'ism holding me back. I need to keep that in my head as I get back into a routine, so it doesn't become too routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, if I could find my work ID, this would all be a lot more straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="leave"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="brain"></category></entry><entry><title>August 23rd 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-23rd-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-23T22:24:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-23T22:24:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-23:/august-23rd-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140823-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nyowm" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140823-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a lot got done today, which is as it should be. Went for a wee motorcycle ride, which turned into a spin to, and around the phoenix park. Getting more confident and enjoying it more now that there are fewer moments of pant-shitting terror. More of this this week …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140823-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nyowm" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140823-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a lot got done today, which is as it should be. Went for a wee motorcycle ride, which turned into a spin to, and around the phoenix park. Getting more confident and enjoying it more now that there are fewer moments of pant-shitting terror. More of this this week, I think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="bike"></category></entry><entry><title>August 22nd 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-22nd-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-22T19:06:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-22T19:06:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-22:/august-22nd-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140822-house.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Clean Lines" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140822-house.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; this is the last of the work on the new house. Today, the painting of the exterior finished, the plumbing was finished inside, and the garage/shed got alarmed (we quickly calmed it down). Just in time for a week left in my time off work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that's …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140822-house.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Clean Lines" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140822-house.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; this is the last of the work on the new house. Today, the painting of the exterior finished, the plumbing was finished inside, and the garage/shed got alarmed (we quickly calmed it down). Just in time for a week left in my time off work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that's left is to clear out the old house of stuff I care about, and point the "Make ready for new tenants" ray-gun at it, care of the local letting agent. Hopefully I'll get that done early next week, just in time for a few days off with nothing to do before going back to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, all in all, that despite the house move taking up a big chunk of my 2 months off, I'm still an awful lot happier with how things have turned out than if I'd kept trying to do it while working full-time. I can't imagine having done all this properly with only evenings and weekends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll do a proper write-up of thoughts on this at some point, this margin cannot contain, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="house"></category></entry><entry><title>August 20th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-20th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-20T01:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-20T01:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-20:/august-20th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140820-pewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pew! Pew!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140820-pewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep cycle being fucked up. That's the holiday sensation I know so well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was at a large (well, the largest of its kind in Ireland), &lt;a href="http://troops-in-contact.com/"&gt;Airsoft game&lt;/a&gt;, which meant a lot of driving and walking around, and not a lot of sleep. My feeble hu-man body is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140820-pewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pew! Pew!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140820-pewpew.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep cycle being fucked up. That's the holiday sensation I know so well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I was at a large (well, the largest of its kind in Ireland), &lt;a href="http://troops-in-contact.com/"&gt;Airsoft game&lt;/a&gt;, which meant a lot of driving and walking around, and not a lot of sleep. My feeble hu-man body is still getting over it, via some seriously lazy weekdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow should see the beginnings of the hideous sickly-yellow colour the previous owners painted the outside of the house disappearing, to be replaced by a hopefully less sickly light green. I am not pretending to be even remotely competent at painting, so we're getting someone in to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me, I've been taking the last few weeks of my leave to spend time with favourite lady, enjoy the new place, and get to some nerding -- I've been messing about with LightwaveRF and getting it working nicely with my existing z-wave setup (and learning LUA and writing more golang in the process). More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="airsoft"></category><category term="house"></category><category term="nerd"></category></entry><entry><title>August 10th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-10th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-10T18:21:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-10T18:21:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-10:/august-10th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140810-nom.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nom!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140810-nom.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week between updates, but it's been a reasonably busy one. Still moving a bunch of stuff from the old house, still trying to get out on the (motor)bike every day or so (in between impressive rainshowers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was a small get-together with some folks, as a bit of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140810-nom.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nom!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140810-nom.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week between updates, but it's been a reasonably busy one. Still moving a bunch of stuff from the old house, still trying to get out on the (motor)bike every day or so (in between impressive rainshowers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was a small get-together with some folks, as a bit of a "Yep, I definitely live here now" wake-up call. The smaller touches are also happening, like home automation and the like. I think tis is possibly the first day I've been able to sit in the office and get some solid nerding done. I'm currently experimenting with using &lt;a href="http://www.lightwaverf.co.uk/"&gt;LightwaveRF&lt;/a&gt; stuff for light switches, since their switch gear is a bit cheaper and more predictable tan z-wave (which I'm using for everything else).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, I have to sort out some smaller bits (like the CCTV company that have left me waiting a solid 3 weeks to finish an install. Bad show, &lt;a href="ttp://www.macalarms.ie/"&gt;MAC Alarms&lt;/a&gt;). Also, some more moving (I still havent'e mptied the old house. The last big job is getting that rented out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the nerd-mobile.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="house"></category><category term="nerd"></category></entry><entry><title>August 3rd 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/august-3rd-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-08-03T11:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-08-03T11:40:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-08-03:/august-3rd-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140803-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Vroom" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140803-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates getting more infrequent, so I should make it my business to do more interesting things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday and friday were the &lt;a href="http://www.rsa.ie/en/RSA/Learner-Drivers/Motorcyclists/Initial-basic-training-IBT-for-motorcyclists/"&gt;IBT&lt;/a&gt; course, which I passed, making me apparently eligible to ride a motorycle of any size without restriction, as long as I wear a newbie hi-vis. That seems …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140803-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Vroom" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140803-bike.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Updates getting more infrequent, so I should make it my business to do more interesting things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday and friday were the &lt;a href="http://www.rsa.ie/en/RSA/Learner-Drivers/Motorcyclists/Initial-basic-training-IBT-for-motorcyclists/"&gt;IBT&lt;/a&gt; course, which I passed, making me apparently eligible to ride a motorycle of any size without restriction, as long as I wear a newbie hi-vis. That seems kind of terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I picked up the rest of the bike gear/PPE, so all I'm missing now is a bike. And for this rain to feck off so it's safe to ride it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week looks like it's moving the rest of the stuff from the old house, and finding a rental agency that wants to turn the old house from a mess into paying tenants. Possibly interspersed with bike shopping, but there's no rush on that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="bike"></category><category term="house"></category></entry><entry><title>July 30th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-30th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-30T16:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-30T16:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-30:/july-30th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140730-attic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="So Cable" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140730-attic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thge last few days haven't felt like particularly urgent ones, which is good -- I think I'm winding down the urgency level overall, and the time off work is kicking in. I had originally intended to take a month off, and was convinced to take 2 by a co-worker. In retrospect …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140730-attic.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="So Cable" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140730-attic.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thge last few days haven't felt like particularly urgent ones, which is good -- I think I'm winding down the urgency level overall, and the time off work is kicking in. I had originally intended to take a month off, and was convinced to take 2 by a co-worker. In retrospect, only taking a month would have been a mistake. I think I'm only really getting into things now, 4 weeks in. Having to go back to work next monday would be bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The computers/gear/network gubbins are mostly set up in the new place, which makes things more tolerable entertainment-wise. The software side of it will come together - I use &lt;a href="https://github.com/gerrowadat/angryweetabix"&gt;angryweetabix&lt;/a&gt; to do a lot of the automation stuff, and will have to do stuff like turn downloads off while I'm at home (Internet connection going from 200Mb-&amp;gt;6Mb), and various other bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next few days are a bit busier, my bike training is tomorrow, and Favourite Lady gets home as well. Hopefully updates will pick up.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 27th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-27th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-27T23:12:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-27T23:12:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-27:/july-27th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140727-strangerwindowsill.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Monorail Cat" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140727-strangerwindowsill.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 and 27 have been days off. I said before about needing to take 'days off' from the moving and the Stuff I Gotta Do - these days turned out that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night, I got one of the annoying headaches I get if I get too tired or stressed, so …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140727-strangerwindowsill.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Monorail Cat" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140727-strangerwindowsill.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 and 27 have been days off. I said before about needing to take 'days off' from the moving and the Stuff I Gotta Do - these days turned out that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday night, I got one of the annoying headaches I get if I get too tired or stressed, so that, if nothing else, was the sign that it was time for a break. So, yesterday and today was mostly lounging around, being amused by the cats noticing things. There's a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; more wildlife outside the windows of this house (more kinds of birds, rabbits and hares, and a local cat they haven't seen yet). It's been a tiring experience when you've got lots of things to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ping has stopped hiding, at least, which is encouraging. She's more of a creature of habit, and didn't explore the house at all the first day. She's currently trotting around smelling things, so that's good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I get to do some delicious physical labour, moving things from the old house, and moving lumber and various bits from the back garden to the site of the skip I really must get for it one of these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is probably the first week with nothign house-related scheduled -- the only thing scheduled is my &lt;a href="http://www.rsa.ie/en/RSA/Learner-Drivers/Motorcyclists/Initial-basic-training-IBT-for-motorcyclists/"&gt;IBT&lt;/a&gt; course on thurs/fri, and some &lt;a href="http://www.wizards.com/dnd/dndnext.aspx"&gt;nerd stuff&lt;/a&gt; on thursday evening. That'll do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 25th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-25th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-25T13:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-25T13:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-25:/july-25th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140725-stranger.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Duncare, skritches plz" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140725-stranger.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Moving Day for small cats everywhere. As predicted, Stranger didn't care and just wanted her head scratched, and Ping stared bloody murder and found some hiding places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overnight was uneventful, aside from the CCTV making noises at 0330 and complaining about SMART errors. Guess it doesn't like being …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140725-stranger.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Duncare, skritches plz" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140725-stranger.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Moving Day for small cats everywhere. As predicted, Stranger didn't care and just wanted her head scratched, and Ping stared bloody murder and found some hiding places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overnight was uneventful, aside from the CCTV making noises at 0330 and complaining about SMART errors. Guess it doesn't like being on its side. Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am generally being around so the cats can have some semblance of normality, and I can catch up on lounging. Some goodies arrived from &lt;a href="http://www.vesternet.com/"&gt;Vesternet&lt;/a&gt; so I'm going to take a ook at that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I'm reading &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finder_(comics)"&gt;The Finder Library&lt;/a&gt; and enjoying the sun while it lasts. The cats are making various sorties into the rest of the house and being hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140725-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Do not know if want" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140725-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 23rd 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-23rd-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-23T09:38:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-23T09:38:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-23:/july-23rd-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140723-jcb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chop chop, Dig Dig" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140723-jcb.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, some dudes in a JCB showed up outside the gate to fill in a giant pothole that trucks and buses had been disappearing down for the last few months. It is my understanding that I should figure out who caused this to happen and then vote for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140723-jcb.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chop chop, Dig Dig" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140723-jcb.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, some dudes in a JCB showed up outside the gate to fill in a giant pothole that trucks and buses had been disappearing down for the last few months. It is my understanding that I should figure out who caused this to happen and then vote for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very last of the work on the house drags oooooon. Today, an electrician does a number of small jobs, which sorts that out (and turns the tiny pointless room containing the entrance to the attic into a decent comms room). Tomorrow (hopefully) a plumber gets to drain and rebalance my radiators in order to fix a tiny drip from one of the radiator valves. The CCTV also gets finished off either today or tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140723-organise.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="ORGANOIZE" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140723-organise.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I am an awful lot more moved-in than I was. The cats are used to me disappearing for a few days at a time, so them moving later in the week is fine, I think.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 20th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-20th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-21T12:46:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-21T12:46:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-21:/july-20th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140720-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mew" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140720-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have moved, the cats have not. This means they get really needy when I'm in the old house. See above for an example: I sat down and Ping immediately sat on my arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House business: More furniture has arrived, the blinds and CCTV are being installed tomorrow (if people …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140720-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Mew" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140720-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have moved, the cats have not. This means they get really needy when I'm in the old house. See above for an example: I sat down and Ping immediately sat on my arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House business: More furniture has arrived, the blinds and CCTV are being installed tomorrow (if people show up). Then the Cats may move, since all that's left is some electrical work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other business: Went to see "Monty Python Live (almost)" in VUE in Liffey Valley. Some nice touches added to the older bits, and they knew which bits to go Just Too Far on (and it was either abundantly clear that Cleese didn't want to be there, or he was putting it on really convincingly).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 17th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-17th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-17T23:17:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-17T23:17:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-17:/july-17th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140717-microwave.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cook cook" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140717-microwave.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever want to get funny looks in an electronics shop, break out a measuring tape and start measuring microwaves. I got an incredulous "They're all standard sizes" today in Power City, while standing in front of a load of microwaves that were clearly Very Different Sizes. Our old …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140717-microwave.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cook cook" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140717-microwave.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever want to get funny looks in an electronics shop, break out a measuring tape and start measuring microwaves. I got an incredulous "They're all standard sizes" today in Power City, while standing in front of a load of microwaves that were clearly Very Different Sizes. Our old microwave (which I actually saw on sale for an eye-watering amount) is too big for the fancy flippy arrangement in the new kitchen, so I got one that physically fits, and performs the one function of a microwave I've ever used ("Nuke on full power for N minutes"). The old microwave was also a browner, grill, and worryingly had a button marked 'Chaos Defrost'. So it gets flogged/donated/something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also today was the &lt;a href="http://www.seai.ie/Your_Building/BER/"&gt;BER&lt;/a&gt; assessor looking at the house post-renovations. His only on-the-spot recommandations were something like "Eh, there are still one or two bulbs that aren't CFLs, and that's about it". So that's good. This assesment means free gubmint money to cover some small part of the heating/insulation work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was planning on tomorrow being a day off, but the solar installers never showed today, and some furniture is arriving tomorrow, as I found out today (2 weeks early!). Maybe I'll gt the weekend off?&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 16th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-16th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-17T09:35:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-17T09:35:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-17:/july-16th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140716-damacy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Why do I own this?!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140716-damacy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I own a sealed copy of Katamari Damacy for the PS2. You find these things out when you're moving and doing a cull of crap. Why do I own this? I don't even own a PS2 any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was probably most of the day. That, and being asleep. I've …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140716-damacy.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Why do I own this?!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140716-damacy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I own a sealed copy of Katamari Damacy for the PS2. You find these things out when you're moving and doing a cull of crap. Why do I own this? I don't even own a PS2 any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was probably most of the day. That, and being asleep. I've found that between one thing and another, I'm still having to get up in the morning. This is, as they say, not what I signed up for. Going to have to sort that one out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evening saw some &lt;a href="http://www.irishairsoft.ie/"&gt;shooting of people&lt;/a&gt;, and then to bed for a delightful 5 hour nap, in time for getting up for the last of the builders (turning on the solar system, and the BER assessment).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 15th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-15th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-15T21:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-15T21:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-15:/july-15th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140715-bed.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bed!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140715-bed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today turned out a good bit more productive than expected. Headed up to Newry for some shopping (Well, for a particular item), then got back and did some painting --  Blinds are arriving on Friday hopefully, so the reveals around the windows needed to be painted before then. Good old Magnolia …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140715-bed.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bed!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140715-bed.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today turned out a good bit more productive than expected. Headed up to Newry for some shopping (Well, for a particular item), then got back and did some painting --  Blinds are arriving on Friday hopefully, so the reveals around the windows needed to be painted before then. Good old Magnolia. The safe bet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This evening is my first night spent sleeping in the new house. I have to say it feels a bit strange not to be surrounded by other people in houses attached to mine. Getting used to the noises of a new house, the random settling and banging noises throughout, the outside noises seeping in. Compared to the house in Clane, it's deathly quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, I'm actually not sure what's on the cards. I've been asked to do some driving instruction, and will be going &lt;a href="http://www.irishairsoft.ie/"&gt;shooting people&lt;/a&gt; in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also need to book some training. Check out what I bought in Newry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140715-helmeh.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Helmet!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140715-helmeh.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 14th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-14th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-14T21:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-14T21:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-14:/july-14th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140714-fire.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Feet up" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140714-fire.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eating an actual meal in what was essentially a building site a week or so ago is a strange experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, today was waaaaay less productive than I thought it would be -- the last vestiges of Builder disapeared (the skip full of old stuff), and I got a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140714-fire.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Feet up" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140714-fire.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eating an actual meal in what was essentially a building site a week or so ago is a strange experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, today was waaaaay less productive than I thought it would be -- the last vestiges of Builder disapeared (the skip full of old stuff), and I got a new freezer. Aside from that I played a bunch of &lt;a href="http://us.battle.net/hearthstone/en/"&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/a&gt;, which I'm not sure I like yet, and moved a few small bits from house to house. Tomorrow will be probably a writeoff too, going to do some shopping...&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 13th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-13th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-13T21:48:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-13T21:48:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-13:/july-13th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140713-chairs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chairs" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140713-chairs.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As old-house starts looking less like a house, new-house starts looking like a way better house than old-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I bought new glasses, discovered that my prescription hasn't changed in 3 years (which I think is good), and then unpacked some nice chairs and a table we ordered a while …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140713-chairs.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chairs" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140713-chairs.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As old-house starts looking less like a house, new-house starts looking like a way better house than old-house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I bought new glasses, discovered that my prescription hasn't changed in 3 years (which I think is good), and then unpacked some nice chairs and a table we ordered a while back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, back to old-house, and coming home to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140713-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lazy cat" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140713-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect tomorrow may be a mostly-day-off. I need to get back on the bike again, and this weekend has been hectic. Weekends and weekdays haven't blurred into a meaningless amalgam just yet, so I need to get on that!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 12th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-12th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-12T20:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-12T20:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-12:/july-12th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140712-boxes.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Boxes" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140712-boxes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Busy day yesterday (and less busy today) so catching up today. The large furniture parts are moved, and some other stuff was delivered (this is a table and chairs). Lead times on furniture are up to a month or so, so this'll keep happening over the next while. I was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140712-boxes.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Boxes" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140712-boxes.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Busy day yesterday (and less busy today) so catching up today. The large furniture parts are moved, and some other stuff was delivered (this is a table and chairs). Lead times on furniture are up to a month or so, so this'll keep happening over the next while. I was able to get a little bit done, but these are mostly still boxes in a corridor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140712-wine.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Wine" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140712-wine.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, headed into Swords to a birthday thing for an Airsoft-buddy. I'm not usually a pub person, because I usually have a work or driving excuse, but I figured that this is the closest to a complete absence of an excuse I'll have, so I actually showed up. The plan was to be dirty stopouts, then up in the morning for some shoot shoots. That worked out delightfully, followed by some helping J and Oli move, followed by crashing on their spare bed for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home now, and having to face the terrifying prospect of an evening without television (it's still here, but I'm not arsed plugging it in). Tomorrow, there are some new-house bits to do, and some more J/Oli moving (their old place is close to Croker, so we have to wait for the bogger concentration to die down in the evening).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 10th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-10th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-10T23:57:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T23:57:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-10:/july-10th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140710-arbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Arbit" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140710-arbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2nd Van Day, and the old house is even barer. This will probably be my last sleep there. The cats get to stay here a while longer, until I have some painting and DIY and other non-cat-friendly stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new house has what we assume is a colony of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140710-arbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Arbit" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140710-arbit.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2nd Van Day, and the old house is even barer. This will probably be my last sleep there. The cats get to stay here a while longer, until I have some painting and DIY and other non-cat-friendly stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new house has what we assume is a colony of wild rabbits nearby, we usually scatter one or two whenever we walk around the back. They came in handy today when we left out some cuttings from a tree in the front, which they duly disposed of by nibbling and running around nervously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow I get solar panels turned on, and get to make a lot of phone calls (one of which will be about my being largely unable to make mobile phone calls in the new house. So Rural.).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 9th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-9th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-09T23:32:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-09T23:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-09:/july-9th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140709-bellurganjeep.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Brum brum" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140709-bellurganjeep.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting to move. First, large furniture items, so rented another van from another place, and moved bed, TV stuff, various other bits. A slight oversight means I don't have a functional bed anywhere. Thankfully, I have a nice couch. It feels a lot more real and the house in Clane …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140709-bellurganjeep.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Brum brum" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140709-bellurganjeep.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting to move. First, large furniture items, so rented another van from another place, and moved bed, TV stuff, various other bits. A slight oversight means I don't have a functional bed anywhere. Thankfully, I have a nice couch. It feels a lot more real and the house in Clane feels a lot more bare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, headed up to Bellurgan for a site walkaround and meeting about a large &lt;a href="http://www.irishairsoft.ie"&gt;Airsoft&lt;/a&gt; game, &lt;a href="http://www.troops-in-contact.com/"&gt;The Rionegro Insurgency&lt;/a&gt;, I'm helping with running next month. Five weeks to go, and surely more about this as the time gets nearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep time. I have the Van tomorrow again, so will get the last of the large stuff moved, and can then move smaller bits at my leisure (this is the theory).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 8th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-8th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-08T21:46:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-08T21:46:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-08:/july-8th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140708-rentalvan.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Brum brum" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140708-rentalvan.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple day in one way. Helped J move cats and possessions, rented a van and negotiated extremely tiny streets with same. Only managed to knock the wing mirror off once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breakfast in a &lt;a href="http://www.canajun.eu/"&gt;pretty terrible canadian place&lt;/a&gt; and afternoon-food in &lt;a href="http://www.woodstockcafe.ie/"&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;, which never disappoints. Om nom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading out in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140708-rentalvan.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Brum brum" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140708-rentalvan.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple day in one way. Helped J move cats and possessions, rented a van and negotiated extremely tiny streets with same. Only managed to knock the wing mirror off once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breakfast in a &lt;a href="http://www.canajun.eu/"&gt;pretty terrible canadian place&lt;/a&gt; and afternoon-food in &lt;a href="http://www.woodstockcafe.ie/"&gt;Woodstock&lt;/a&gt;, which never disappoints. Om nom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heading out in the morning to pick up the van for my own move, of at least large pieces of furniture that don't fit in the jeep. Oh joy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 7th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-7th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-07T22:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-07T22:40:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-07:/july-7th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140707-paintroller.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Painty paint paint" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140707-paintroller.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another late morning. I am entitled. The only useful thing that happened today was painting one of the bedrooms. Tomorrow I get to drive a giant van around, helping J move to a new place. I then go get a different giant van for a few days to move my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140707-paintroller.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Painty paint paint" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140707-paintroller.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another late morning. I am entitled. The only useful thing that happened today was painting one of the bedrooms. Tomorrow I get to drive a giant van around, helping J move to a new place. I then go get a different giant van for a few days to move my larger items. It's giant van week! So excite.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 5th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-5th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-06T14:36:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-06T14:36:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-06:/july-5th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No photo today. If there was, it'd be a soiled lab coat with some scary-looking weaponry on it. Went to an afternoon/evening/overnight &lt;a href="http://www.irishairsoft.ie/"&gt;Airsoft&lt;/a&gt; game, with a Walking Dead theme -- I got to stick on a lab coat and pretend to do unspeakable things to walkers in a loft …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;No photo today. If there was, it'd be a soiled lab coat with some scary-looking weaponry on it. Went to an afternoon/evening/overnight &lt;a href="http://www.irishairsoft.ie/"&gt;Airsoft&lt;/a&gt; game, with a Walking Dead theme -- I got to stick on a lab coat and pretend to do unspeakable things to walkers in a loft. This went on until 3am or so. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm only out of bed now, which gives me a low-level anxiety about wasting the day still. I've been trying to intentionally take some days off from "Things I have to do" for "Things I'd like to do", and this may end up being one. As of tomorrow, I have No Excuse Whatsoever to not move house, so today may well be not doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 4th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-4th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-04T12:02:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-04T12:02:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-04:/july-4th-2014.html</id><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140703-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Kitchen" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140703-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a slight hiccup on the home stretch (a plumber having a go at drilling a hole in a ceramic sink, and succeeding against all odds), the house buildings works are done, finished, kaputt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it's time for minor DIY plus moving, no more excuses. Also furniture shopping. Joy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>July 1st 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/july-1st-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-07-01T22:47:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-07-01T22:47:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-07-01:/july-1st-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140701-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Kitchen" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140701-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipped a day, yesterday being mostly lost to what I'm assuming were sinus headaches, but which could have been stress or tiredness or a combination of both. Last time I bought a house, I ended up on a treadmill in a local clinic having some heart palpitations checked out. So …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140701-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Kitchen" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140701-kitchen.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipped a day, yesterday being mostly lost to what I'm assuming were sinus headaches, but which could have been stress or tiredness or a combination of both. Last time I bought a house, I ended up on a treadmill in a local clinic having some heart palpitations checked out. So things are going pretty well, considering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was Kitchen day, the installers arriving first thing (as well as the Alarm guy, so now my alarm will send me a frantic SMS message if it goes off). After only slight mishaps (the hole in the ceiling for the extractor fan was measured based off old plans, so was a bit off. Whoops) I now have some of a kitchen. The main bits (sink, hob, oven) will go in hopefully tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had new washer and drier delivered, and got to hear an entertaining rant from the delivery guy (apparently 'Robertstown' is some vague amalgam of a couple of townlands that can mean any where from just outside Naas to Enfield, so about 30 square km). A happy throwback to living in town is that I'm able to give directions to my house via well-known local pubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also primed/sealed some plaster reveals in the rooms I didn't have profesionally painted, and hung some curtain rails. Aren't I a clever primate. I also now own a spirit level you could beat someone to death with (which, in fairness, is a critical criterion for any hand tool).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, since the actual tradespeople don't arrive until the evening, I'm going to take a day off house stuff. I actually haven't had a proper lie-in since my leave started, so I'm going to try that, then see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>June 29th 2014</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/june-29th-2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-29T20:13:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-29T20:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-29:/june-29th-2014.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My capacity to think of a witty title for every day is going to run dry eventully, so let's try this for a title convention -- protip: posts with the date as a title probably either have limited re-sale value or were boring in the first place :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My capacity to think of a witty title for every day is going to run dry eventully, so let's try this for a title convention -- protip: posts with the date as a title probably either have limited re-sale value or were boring in the first place :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went and played some Airsoft, then met J in &lt;a href="http://www.ikea.ie/"&gt;IKEA&lt;/a&gt; and picked up a few small bits (no furniture yet, or at all from IKEA if I get my way), then headed home via seeing the new floor. This was the last unfinished surface in the house, the walls and ceilings having been finished yesterday post-windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was a big floor (spanning two rooms), we decided to go fairly swish, and weren't disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140629-floor.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Floor!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140629-floor.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="/images/20140629-floor2.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Floor!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140629-floor2.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>Must Do Things</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/must-do-things.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-28T19:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-28T19:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-28:/must-do-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm guessing it's going to take at least a week to figure out that I don't have a schedule. Sadly, house renovations mean I actually do have a schedule of people showing up for the next week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I failed to sell an Oven, and succeeded in buying …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm guessing it's going to take at least a week to figure out that I don't have a schedule. Sadly, house renovations mean I actually do have a schedule of people showing up for the next week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I failed to sell an Oven, and succeeded in buying a new Airsoft gun. So there's something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also lit the first fire in the new house, coincidentally because I needed to dry the place out for a floor that's being laid tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140628-hearth.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Fire!" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140628-hearth.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>Last Day O' School</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/last-day-o-school.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-27T22:37:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-27T22:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-27:/last-day-o-school.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished up in work today, not in again until the 1st September. Wandered around doing some house stuff (measuring windows for blinds, seeing if stuff needs doing tomorrow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next wek, the interior painting gets finished, along with the new kitchen arriving tuesday, and the last of the floors going down …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finished up in work today, not in again until the 1st September. Wandered around doing some house stuff (measuring windows for blinds, seeing if stuff needs doing tomorrow).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next wek, the interior painting gets finished, along with the new kitchen arriving tuesday, and the last of the floors going down. We're then well into 'no excuse' territory :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Googlers who are following this: I should warn you -- it's not going to involve much highbrow insight until I sort out this block and tackle. Right now, this is "My Project", if you've read the excellent &lt;a href="http://randsinrepose.com/archives/the-nerd-handbook/"&gt;Nerd Handbook&lt;/a&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also going to be doing something essentially every day, as much as I can. I'm considering adding &lt;a href="http://www.disqus.com/"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; so people can comment, but in the meantime, email me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, I'm tired. It's been a logn day of work. Time for a new start tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>Ow</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/ow.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-24T21:26:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-24T21:26:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-24:/ow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally (I am a male Irish person, after all. We're allergic to health professionals) went to the Physio today for a niggling problem I've had with one of my calves for the last while. What I thought was a bit of stiffness due to lack of exercise and a need …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Finally (I am a male Irish person, after all. We're allergic to health professionals) went to the Physio today for a niggling problem I've had with one of my calves for the last while. What I thought was a bit of stiffness due to lack of exercise and a need to HTFU is actually &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Achilles_tendinitis"&gt;Achilles Tendinitis&lt;/a&gt;, which is a lot more scientific of a diagnosis. Icepacks and stretches for a while. Just in time for wanting to use my calves a bunch, yay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, figured out the last big renovation job on the house (a floor in two of the rooms). A good bit more than I was expecting to spend, but should be commensurately nicer. All things going well, we could be done by end of next week. Could be. All things going well. Yep.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="house"></category></entry><entry><title>Don't Forget: You're Here Forever</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/dont-forget-youre-here-forever.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-23T19:28:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-23T19:28:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-23:/dont-forget-youre-here-forever.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140623-10years.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Snazzy." src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140623-10years.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some zealous schwag-merchant deep in the innards of The Company was a month early with this -- probably giving me some time to mount it over the mantel of my plush leather and mahogony office before the big day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, I'll not be in work for the big day -- I'm taking …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140623-10years.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Snazzy." src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140623-10years.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some zealous schwag-merchant deep in the innards of The Company was a month early with this -- probably giving me some time to mount it over the mantel of my plush leather and mahogony office before the big day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, I'll not be in work for the big day -- I'm taking all of July and August off, so generally chill out, catch up on being lazy, and have more than 2 weeks off for the first time in my working life. I figure after 15 years or so I'm probably overdue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally, my list of things to do for the two months amount to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move into new house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rent out old house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ride my bike a bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe get a new hat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems like a solid set of objectives. I have vague plans to write more code, play more music, replay some games I've been meaning to. Anything after that seems like overachieving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this week saw lots of mail show up at the office, some of which is being squirreled away for hacking on later. Today, the &lt;a href="http://www.spark.io/"&gt;Spark&lt;/a&gt; board arrived, which will be fun, if I decide what to do with it at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140623-spark.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Double-Snazzy." src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140623-spark.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of being able to talk over the network to stuff that's not supposed to is fascinating (which is why I've also picked up some z-wave toys for the new house, which I'll get to). This will be fun to mess with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="log"></category><category term="work"></category><category term="google"></category></entry><entry><title>Ta-ta</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/ta-ta.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-21T17:13:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-21T17:13:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-21:/ta-ta.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having nothing to write about but "I made soup!" is something of a dampener on things (I didn't make soup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the point of this log is to capture some of that upcoming leave of absence I'm taking from work - I'm taking all of July and August off, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having nothing to write about but "I made soup!" is something of a dampener on things (I didn't make soup).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the point of this log is to capture some of that upcoming leave of absence I'm taking from work - I'm taking all of July and August off, and this is my last week in work before
turning into a pumpkin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The general idea is that if I've got nothing to write about every day or two, then I should probably be doing more stuff. I've put off a lot of things over the years, I should at least clear some things (I haven't made a list intentionally - that kind of invites disappointment, I think).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, today was mostly sleeping and dealing with Jetlag. Tomorrow, hopefully less so.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="weekend"></category><category term="log"></category></entry><entry><title>Excuse the Dust</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/excuse-the-dust.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-19T17:06:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-19T17:06:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-19:/excuse-the-dust.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Still fiddling with Pelican -- it's got a reasonably nice codebase, but the devs don't appear to be all that responsive. I've had to patch a few of their outstanding
pull requests already to get things working just-so, &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/pull/187"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; most notably. Also some fiddling with setting up a lightbox for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Still fiddling with Pelican -- it's got a reasonably nice codebase, but the devs don't appear to be all that responsive. I've had to patch a few of their outstanding
pull requests already to get things working just-so, &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican-plugins/pull/187"&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; most notably. Also some fiddling with setting up a lightbox for images, and importing old stuff from Blogger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140619-nycsky.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Videoconference Selfie" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140619-nycsky.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today in NYC wasn't as oppressively hot as yesterday (and probably about the same as at home. I think I might have missed the Irish summer in my 3-day trip away). At least they're less apologetic about air conditioning here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20140619-gvc.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Videoconference Selfie" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20140619-gvc.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more day here and I get to go see if my new house is still standing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="photo"></category><category term="nyc"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry><entry><title>Tap tap tap</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/tap-tap-tap.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-06-18T21:39:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-06-18T21:39:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2014-06-18:/tap-tap-tap.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here's another attempt at keeping a log of some kind. &lt;a href="http://blog.swearing.org/"&gt;the last one&lt;/a&gt; died because I stopped having (what I saw as) interesting things on it, blogger's editor bugged the fuck out of me, and general forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my problem with having a web log is in the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So here's another attempt at keeping a log of some kind. &lt;a href="http://blog.swearing.org/"&gt;the last one&lt;/a&gt; died because I stopped having (what I saw as) interesting things on it, blogger's editor bugged the fuck out of me, and general forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of my problem with having a web log is in the min-maxing of content -- you either detail every last thing and risk (hell, more than risk) being boring, or you hold out until you have some earth-shattering insight, and every post has to have one of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This race to the middle has been the death of previous attempts, I think. This time around I'm going to try to do something, anything on a regular basis. The aspiration is daily, or several times a week. We'll see how often it is. It's going to be boring and not-boring in about equal measure, I hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also going to see if I can hack a bit on &lt;a href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/en/latest/quickstart.html"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to see how it can munge some of the metadata I provide. I've been doing 'snippets' at work using markdown for a while, and have found it useful for grepping. The source files for this should hopefully be useful in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Meta"></category><category term="meta"></category></entry><entry><title>Using GMail as a relay with Postfix</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/using-gmail-as-a-relay-with-postfix.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-07-22T17:25:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-07-22T17:25:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-07-22:/using-gmail-as-a-relay-with-postfix.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I fiddled a bit with this, so I thought I'd do a no-nonsense guide to
doing this. There are other guides, but a lot of them are incomplete and
will leave you with queueing issues or annoyances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The science bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_use_tls&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_auth_enable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_password_maps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;etc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;postfix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;sasl_passwd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_security_options …&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I fiddled a bit with this, so I thought I'd do a no-nonsense guide to
doing this. There are other guides, but a lot of them are incomplete and
will leave you with queueing issues or annoyances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The science bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_use_tls&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_auth_enable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_password_maps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;etc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;postfix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;sasl_passwd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_security_options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;noanonymous&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_sasl_tls_security_options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;noanonymous&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Send all mail through smtp.gmail.com&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;relayhost&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gmail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Stop getting a catpcha, hopefully.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp_destination_rate_delay&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;relay_destination_rate_delay&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, edit /etc/postfix/sasl_passwd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;smtp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gmail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;myemail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nd"&gt;@gmail&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;MyPaSsWoRd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn't have to be an @gmail account,
it can be a GAFYD account, once you've logged into it once to activate
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then just generate the map file for the
sasl_passwd file and reload. As root:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;postmap&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;sasl_passwd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;postfix&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;reload&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you're done. Monitor your queue a few
times over the first few days to make sure stupid stuff hasn't happened
(the delay between mails might get tweaked), but in general this has
worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="gmail"></category><category term="postfix"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Alive and Thinkin'</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/alive-and-thinkin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-05-26T13:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-05-26T13:55:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-05-26:/alive-and-thinkin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am alive. Apologies to folks who were following the electronics stuff
-- the short version is that it worked, although I didn't get to use it
'in anger' as such. The other thing I learned is that when traveling
through UK customs on the week of a royal wedding, having …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am alive. Apologies to folks who were following the electronics stuff
-- the short version is that it worked, although I didn't get to use it
'in anger' as such. The other thing I learned is that when traveling
through UK customs on the week of a royal wedding, having a small
plastic box with wires coming out of it and a 9v battery strapped to it
with tape is not a clever thing to have in your car (thankfully the
customs official had a sense of humour).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I've been doing a bunch of for-money work, and only took time
out this week to relax. I occasionally take a week off to hang around at
home and get 'life administrivia' done. Think of it as a concrete block
on the see-saw of work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been playing around a bit with generalised messaging for
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Home_automation"&gt;domotics&lt;/a&gt; updates. I'm thinking of a centralised controller that can
accept events from various signals, such as the &lt;a href="http://www.currentcost.com/"&gt;Current Cost&lt;/a&gt; meter,
a wifi device coming in range, or a small IC hanging off the doorbell
circuit, for example. A lot of these devices don't have particularly
fully-functional network stacks, so I'll have to bite the bullet and get
the handful of ZigBee radios I got recently working. Doorbell will be
the fun one, I think. My house already has a (private) twitter account,
and DMs me for various stuff (unknown hosts grabbing a DHCP lease on the
network, etc.). Adding more stuff to this is the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also interested in the idea of cloud applications with local storage
or local encryption keys -- so all your data is stored encrypted on the
server side, and only you have the keys, so the content is decrypted at
render-time. Stuff like &lt;a href="http://agilebits.com/onepassword"&gt;1password&lt;/a&gt; does this with secure stuff like
password databases, but I think web browsing machines are zippy enough
to do this for userdata. I have to see if it's been done already (it
probably has), but I want to do some fiddling with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, same old. Too much science to do, never enough time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="brain"></category><category term="electronics"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="twitter"></category><category term="update"></category></entry><entry><title>My Eyes!</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/my-eyes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-15T23:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-04-15T23:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-04-15:/my-eyes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've not had a lot of time to go at electronics in the past while
(mainly a combination of work things and family things kicking my ass),
but I got to some of it tonight -- The clever parts of the design and
build are basically done, so what's left is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've not had a lot of time to go at electronics in the past while
(mainly a combination of work things and family things kicking my ass),
but I got to some of it tonight -- The clever parts of the design and
build are basically done, so what's left is producing the final piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the motion sensor parts, there's also the bright light, to
mess with people's night vision. For this, I got 4 super-bright LEDs,
and did monstrous things with solder to produce a 5x2 header, that was
fully connected along the long side. This gave me the 4 LEDs connected
in parallell. This is pretty bright with the 5v applied from the analog
output of the Arduino:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result will be built on an Arduno Fio board, which only has a
3.3v signal (It's powered off a 3.7v LiPo battery), so I'll need to
amplify that somehow. I'm thinking I might try to power the board and
LEDs off a regular 9V instead, or have the LiPo powering the board and
the 9V powering the buzzer and leds, gated on the signal line of the
board with some transistors. I may be of course talking out my ass. I'm
going to pick up some various transistors over the weekend and
experimenting. My guess is the gate and emitter of a transistor need a
common ground, which won't work with using separate power sources. We'll
see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, deadlines, help. I'm supposed to be using this thing next
saturday. So, full steam ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="airsoft"></category><category term="arduino"></category><category term="electronics"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Finding Day</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/finding-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-03T10:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2011-04-03T10:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-04-03:/finding-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20110403-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Meow" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20110403-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago today, a very small ball of fur decided to mew outside our
front door in particular. We let her in and looked after her for a bit,
and eventually decided she could stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not sure exactly how old she is, we're guessing se was about 6-7 …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/images/20110403-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Meow" src="/images/thumbs/thumbnail_square/20110403-ping.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year ago today, a very small ball of fur decided to mew outside our
front door in particular. We let her in and looked after her for a bit,
and eventually decided she could stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're not sure exactly how old she is, we're guessing se was about 6-7
months when she came to us, but I guess her finding day is as good a day
as any to be happy she's around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy finding day, Ping.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="cat"></category><category term="ping"></category></entry><entry><title>I Seeeeee Youuuuu</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/i-seeeeee-youuuuu.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-25T22:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-25T22:30:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-03-25:/i-seeeeee-youuuuu.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, first steps. I picked up a few &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/products/8630"&gt;PIR Motion sensors&lt;/a&gt;. These are a
specific kind, there are a few other kinds, but they should have
datasheets. You might recognise the bulbous white shape of them from
those motion-sensing light switches. They're about a fiver each and fun
to play …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, first steps. I picked up a few &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/products/8630"&gt;PIR Motion sensors&lt;/a&gt;. These are a
specific kind, there are a few other kinds, but they should have
datasheets. You might recognise the bulbous white shape of them from
those motion-sensing light switches. They're about a fiver each and fun
to play with.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comments section on Sparkfun had a &lt;a href="http://itp.nyu.edu/physcomp/sensors/Reports/PIRMotionSensor"&gt;very good tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on basic
use, but also explains the basic principles of its operation. It has 3
pins -- DC, Ground and Alarm.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Science Bit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alarm pin is what's called an &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open_collector"&gt;Open Collector&lt;/a&gt;, which means it's
either connected to ground, or to 'nothing'. To better understand this,
let's assume you don't know what a transistor is (I know I sure didn't a
few weeks ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking simplistically, a transistor is a component where you can vary
one voltage based on a much smaller voltage. In this way you can amplify
a voltage pretty easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a diagram!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/dc/Transistor2.svg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually transistors are tiny and embedded or are tiny and on a
breadboard, but let's assume for a moment that it's a box with 3 wires
coming out of it. They're called collector, emitter and base. Emitter is
always connected to ground, and provides the reference voltage, or
definition of 'zero'. Base is a small voltage in relation to ground, and
the voltage applied to the base controls how much voltage is allowed
flow between the emitter and the collector. The difference between the
voltage on the base, and the voltage allowed through the collector is
called the 'gain'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However! The voltage on the collector doesn't come from nowhere. It has
to be supplied, and the voltage 'allowed' to flow is defined by the
voltage on the base. So, if you apply 3.3v to the base, and 9v to the
collector (the voltage marked 'V~cc~' on the diagram there), you get a
certain voltage that's actually 'allowed' through the transistor, and
can be used in other applications by connecting them before the resistor
(At 'V~out~' on the diagram).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zig-zaggy thing there on the diagram is a resistor. We put it across
the larger V~cc~ voltage to lower it a bit, since transistors are
usually only rated to take a certain voltage. The function of V~cc~ and
the resistor is to 'pull up' the voltage across the emitter and
collector. This is why the resistor there is often called a 'pull-up
resistor'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transistors are handy for switches when you want to control a large
voltage using a small voltage. They're also useful if you want to take a
tiny voltage you get from a signal somewhere and amplify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, why this is relevant is that an 'Open Collector' is the
collector from a transistor that's available as a signal. However,
instead of usual 'binary' signals that might produce a 'True' voltage or
a 'False' lack of voltage, it's either connected to ground, or not.
Whether or not it is connected to ground depends on the base voltage. My
guess is that the PIR sensor circuitry provides the 'base' voltage and
lets us use any V~cc~ voltage we want, in order to 'pull up' the output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you go look at the circuit diagram and build instructions in the
tutorial mentioned above, it works just so. The one modification I made
here is that as well as pulling up the voltage, instead of connecting
back to the LED on the Arduino board, I connected up to a big old Piezo
Buzzer I got in Maplin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The finished build looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TY0Nl6RxURI/AAAAAAAADfk/kPBdY2IPIUQ/s720/IMG_20110313_212116.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the end result is that when you wave your hand in front of the PIR,
the buzzer makes an annoying noise. Success!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up would be making things a bit smaller -- There are smaller,
cheaper Arduino boards you can get, and I'll do a build soon that's a
little easier to get into a project box and lug around with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="arduino"></category><category term="electronics"></category></entry><entry><title>And All the Hills are Rainbows</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/and-all-the-hills-are-rainbows.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-07T02:51:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-07T02:51:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-03-07:/and-all-the-hills-are-rainbows.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Various intricacies of how my job works these days means I work with
people in a bunch of offices. They're not all in the states, but
Mountain View and Irvine are two offices in California I do go to
occasionally. When I was planning a trip to both late last …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Various intricacies of how my job works these days means I work with
people in a bunch of offices. They're not all in the states, but
Mountain View and Irvine are two offices in California I do go to
occasionally. When I was planning a trip to both late last year, I said
I'd look at alternatives to flying for an hour (SFO-&gt;SNA). After doing
some digging, I found the &lt;a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Route_C&amp;amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;amp;cid=1241245648567"&gt;Coast Starlight&lt;/a&gt;, which is an &lt;a href="http://www.amtrak.com/"&gt;Amtrak&lt;/a&gt;
train that goes from Seattle to Los Angeles, and stops in Oakland and
San Jose. It so happens Oakland is a short &lt;a href="http://www.bart.gov/"&gt;BART&lt;/a&gt; ride from SFO, so I
said I'd give it a go.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TXQsjOuup4I/AAAAAAAADYE/egyd_N2BO6A/s720/P1010044.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honestly am ambivalent about the TSA, and being groped and
what-have-you. I realise there's no point in getting angry in Airports,
because the people there are just trying to make a living. I'm also
ambivalent about saving on flying (the plane goes whether I'm on it or
not). I just like trains, and this one promised 12 hours or so of good
geography and comfort. I got myself a '&lt;a href="http://www.amtrak.com/servlet/ContentServer?c=AM_Accommodation_C&amp;amp;pagename=am%2FLayout&amp;amp;p=1237405732517&amp;amp;cid=1241210576173"&gt;roomette&lt;/a&gt;', which is
apparently what you're allowed call a small cupboard with a seat in it,
and it turned out to cost about \$130, which is cheaper than some air
fares SFO-&gt;SNA.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also doesn't help that SNA is referred to in muttered tones as
'Disneyland Airport'. It's right beside Anaheim and the home of The
Mouse, so it's usually packed with kids. The look on a co-worker's face
when they called for people-who-need-extra-time-or-have-small-children,
and half the airport marched onto the plane will stay with me always.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TXQsiAKBXyI/AAAAAAAADbY/dObrAJqlKRg/s720/P1010042.JPG"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The train itself is good and comfy. Tea, coffee, juice on each sleeper
carriage, and a bar and observation carriage which is decent for hanging
out, and "has" "wi-fi" (said wi-fi could well have been using the train
driver's 3G phone as an uplink, and meets the minimum federal
requirement to be called 'wi-fi'). The food is/was reasonably decent,
and some of the views are very pleasant.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TXQsmIOW4OI/AAAAAAAADas/8eTLVJvyp7w/s720/P1010038.JPG"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 hours is a bit of a hike, so it's not recommended if you have actual
places to go, but it's miles more pleasant than the solid 4 hours or so
of wangling door-to-door it'd take to fly, and also trains kick ass.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm in LA for the night, and continuing by train to Irvine tomorrow,
where I will again endure the hilarity of having to rent a car to cross
the road from my hotel to the office. Go California!!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="america"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>Electronics Schwag (The Specifics)</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/electronics-schwag-the-specifics.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-03-02T06:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-03-02T06:24:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-03-02:/electronics-schwag-the-specifics.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A commenter asked me for more specifics on stuff to get when getting
started with electronics, so since I've learned a little since then,
here's my uninformed opinion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Soldering Iron&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a good one. I got a reasonably crap Draper one from Amazon, which
was 25W. It's fine, but takes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A commenter asked me for more specifics on stuff to get when getting
started with electronics, so since I've learned a little since then,
here's my uninformed opinion.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Soldering Iron&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a good one. I got a reasonably crap Draper one from Amazon, which
was 25W. It's fine, but takes a while to heat up and can be a little
while melting the solder, which is annoying when you're holding
everything just-so and it's all perfect except the hot bit isn't hot
enough. If I were doing this again I'd get a 40w one, and one with
adjustable heat.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the soldering tutorials I've seen use a pointed tip on the
soldering iron. I've found the chisel tip a lot easier. I can touch the
tip against a solder point and heat the wire and contact a lot easier
than using a pointed tip (which you don't use the point of anyway). I'd
recommend you try both to see what works.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Solder&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of the online tutorials say "Don't use silver solder or lead-free
solder, it's a pain in the ass to use". Well, thanks to RoHs, lead
solder is at least very hard (if not impossible) to get in Europe. &lt;a href="http://www.rohsusa.com/"&gt;This
crackpot here&lt;/a&gt; has a website talking about it, but you're probably
wasting your time looking for lead solder in Ireland. I found it easy
enough to solder with lead-free, but then again I've no frame of
reference. I just picked up some 60/40 and 63/37 lead solder here in the
bay area, so we'll see once I'm back.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People make a big deal about lead-free solder not being less dangerous
than lead solder. All I know is that if you're burning a solid
metal-looking object and smoke comes out, breathing it in is probably
bad for you. Little pro tip there.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wire Strippers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See this here, right?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://lh4.ggpht.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TW3YD7B3n0I/AAAAAAAADTs/8_rFTwY-Mwo/stripper.jpg?imgmax=800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load of shite. Avoid like the plague. I wasn't able to adjust mine to
strip the wire I got, and it just chomped ineffectually and was big and
annoying.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now see this?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TW3YmDWsgsI/AAAAAAAADTw/9xsBSVLpsW4/wire_stripper.jpg?imgmax=800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bog standard wire stripper, costs a fiver or less, is in pretty much
every electronics set ever. That is because it's the only wire stripper
you'll ever need. Some wire stripper inventor guy is using money to
insulate his attic because of these babies, because they're great. Get
one.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wires&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After talking about wire strippers, of course, I should let you know
that stripping the ends off wires is for suckers. I picked up a &lt;a href="http://www.maplin.co.uk/jump-wire-kit-2014"&gt;Jump
Wire Kit&lt;/a&gt; in Maplin in town, which has a bunch of varying lengths of
wire, especially for breadboarding and the like. I also recommend &lt;a href="http://www.skpang.co.uk/catalog/product_info.php?products_id=386"&gt;this
set of jumper wires&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="http://www.skpang.co.uk/"&gt;SK Pang&lt;/a&gt;, which are even neater (and
cheaper!). For the first while you're probably not going to be soldering
wires in place, so the jump wires are grand.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Breadboards&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breadboards are boards full of holes you stick wires into. If you're
getting one, make sure to get one with a power rail going along each
side, which are much nicer. It should look something like this:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://lh6.ggpht.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TW3bULTgKtI/AAAAAAAADT8/xmi4aUL24N4/halfbb.jpg?imgmax=800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get two or three so you don't have to dismantle something you're doing
to re-use the breadboard.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Arduino Stuff and Components&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main Arduino stuff you want to pick up, barring any particular
project in mind, is one or two (they're small and cheap) boards, the USB
cable you need to talk to them, and some breadboards for fiddling
around.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board you want to get is the Uno, and you may want to avoid the SMD
edition if you can. For a lot of stuff, it won't matter, but the main
difference is you can't remove the microcontroller chip from the SMD
version. There are reasons you may want to do this, which I'll cover in
a later post. The SMD version was mainly produced due to a worldwide
shortage of the Atmega328 chip in the larger removable form factor, so
you're more than likely getting the non-SMD, but it probably doesn't
make a difference. The SMD version apparently has other improvements for
meganerds who want to fiddle with the firmware on the board.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the normal version with the microcontroller chip in a socket on
the board:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TW3hp1B4RxI/AAAAAAAADUQ/x2GXJJJel60/uno.jpg?imgmax=800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the SMD version, notice the tiny surface-mount chip. Same chip,
different form factor. Notice the 6 extra pins near the USB port.
Apparently you can do science with them:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://lh5.ggpht.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TW3h007Q7iI/AAAAAAAADUU/UsjCS2qlfYg/unosmd.jpg?imgmax=800"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also look into getting 'shields' for the board, which are
basically other boards that plug into the Uno. They're good for
prototyping, but can be bigger than what you want when you want to
shrink things down. You can get them for stuff like ethernet, XBee (mesh
networking), and other kinds of wired or wireless comms.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend getting one of the starter kits, the one from &lt;a href="http://www.adafruit.com/"&gt;Adafruit&lt;/a&gt;
is good, comes with everything you need. I also recommend getting a
Proto Shield, which is a good starter soldering project. The Adafruit
starter kit comes with one, and &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/"&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt; do a different one that
does roughly the same thing. While you're getting stuff, have a look
around &lt;a href="http://www.skpang.co.uk/"&gt;SK Pang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.adafruit.com/"&gt;AdaFruit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/"&gt;SparkFun&lt;/a&gt; to see what
they've got, there are a bunch of ready-made projects and widgets
that'll give you ideas for projects. Personally, I picked up some
&lt;a href="http://web.media.mit.edu/~leah/LilyPad/"&gt;LilyPad&lt;/a&gt; stuff for the project I dreamed up (details coming soon) and
an RFID reader chip and breakout board for fiddling with RFID.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more specialised stuff, there are smaller boards you can get, which
end up cheaper than the Uno. The &lt;a href="http://www.skpang.co.uk/catalog/product_info.php?cPath=140_141&amp;amp;products_id=445"&gt;Pro Mini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.skpang.co.uk/catalog/product_info.php?cPath=140_141&amp;amp;products_id=325"&gt;FIO&lt;/a&gt; end up a fiver
or so cheaper per board, and can be good if you have specific things in
mind (I picked up a pair of FIOs, since they have an XBee socket
onboard).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As components go, Maplin do 'lucky bags' of the likes of resistors,
capacitors, etc. If you know exactly what you want, &lt;a href="http://rswww.ie/"&gt;Radionics&lt;/a&gt; have a
large catalogue and do next-day courier delivery in Dublin for a fiver.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up I'll be talking about the project I've been thinking about, and
the bits I've been gradually accumulating for it. I'll also show you the
first few photos I have of my own tinkerings with RFID reading.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="arduino"></category><category term="electronics"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Not bad, as Castles go</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/not-bad-as-castles-go.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-28T18:48:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-02-28T18:48:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-02-28:/not-bad-as-castles-go.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Myself and Favourite Lady took the weekend off to head to &lt;a href="http://www.dromoland.ie/"&gt;Dromoland&lt;/a&gt;
(warning: terrible website will make all your orifices bleed rage). It
was nice to get out to that part of the country again. Roomservice
breakfast while reading the sunday papers is one of the best things
ever.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Myself and Favourite Lady took the weekend off to head to &lt;a href="http://www.dromoland.ie/"&gt;Dromoland&lt;/a&gt;
(warning: terrible website will make all your orifices bleed rage). It
was nice to get out to that part of the country again. Roomservice
breakfast while reading the sunday papers is one of the best things
ever.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had the opportunity to visit Bunratty Castle, which I'd last
visited as a tiny nipper when my dad used to bring school tours there.
We saw some chickens begging for scones.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TWpZX2XPhtI/AAAAAAAADRQ/kNmC2ydVimM/s720/IMG_20110227_135811.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we saw some of the old biscuits known to man. Shows how the old
Kimberley/Mikado/Coconut Cream combination has stood the test.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TWpuwZSvEDI/AAAAAAAADRo/4lWfCmbESLc/s720/IMG_20110227_144554.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I'm flying off to the Bay area for a few weeks to issue barked
instructions to nerds. I have a few posts lined up about the electronics
stuff I'm doing, but they can be spread out over the next few weeks so I
can resume when I get back. Inventing is interesting.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I'm writing this from the Delta Sky Club in JFK, which gets a solid meh
out of ten. The normal-person waiting area has iPads).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="bunratty"></category><category term="chickens"></category><category term="castles"></category><category term="dromoland"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="update"></category></entry><entry><title>Legbone connected to my Wristwatch</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/legbone-connected-to-my-wristwatch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-02-17T16:49:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-02-17T16:49:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2011-02-17:/legbone-connected-to-my-wristwatch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been fiddling about with small electronics recently, specifically
the &lt;a href="http://www.arduino.cc/"&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;, which is a microcontroller/prototyping board. The
boards have gotten way cheap (standard ones are around 20-30 quid, less
if you want fewer I/O ports or a specialised board layout you need to
solder bits onto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been fiddling about with small electronics recently, specifically
the &lt;a href="http://www.arduino.cc/"&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;, which is a microcontroller/prototyping board. The
boards have gotten way cheap (standard ones are around 20-30 quid, less
if you want fewer I/O ports or a specialised board layout you need to
solder bits onto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part, I've found, is thinking of things to make. In the
meantime I'm practicing soldering, using projects like making a few
&lt;a href="http://www.adafruit.com/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;amp;cPath=17_21&amp;amp;products_id=51"&gt;ProtoShields&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="http://www.adafruit.com/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;amp;cPath=17_21&amp;amp;products_id=286"&gt;LOLShield&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night, I made a functional RFID reader, using less than 50 euro
worth of parts, which for a long-time hardware luddite was extremely
fulfilling. I even managed to solder without burning myself or others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/_otzZMGWrd00/TV1ONwxZpjI/AAAAAAAADOk/f3TucijiXUk/s720/IMG_20110216_204106.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've got one or two projects in mind, mainly around wireless sensors and
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Home_automation"&gt;domotics&lt;/a&gt;, which I'll put up here (hey, I have to put something here,
right?).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="arduino"></category><category term="electronics"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="rfid"></category><category term="tech"></category></entry><entry><title>Hibernating</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/hibernating.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-24T13:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-24T13:20:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Conno</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-11-24:/hibernating.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;'Tis the season, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more stint of travel before the long and well-anticipated 2 weeks
off work for xmas. I've only had one unbroken year in the streak of
taking these 2 weeks off before in my entire working life -- I get very
grumpy if it doesn't work out …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;'Tis the season, apparently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more stint of travel before the long and well-anticipated 2 weeks
off work for xmas. I've only had one unbroken year in the streak of
taking these 2 weeks off before in my entire working life -- I get very
grumpy if it doesn't work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last few weeks have been progressively colder at home, so the
heating has been bumped up a notch and the &lt;a href="http://www.theslanket.com/"&gt;Slanket&lt;/a&gt; has been seeing
more and more use. That tiny roundy cat you see above is also starting
to disappear under the duvet for the day when I'm out. Outside, it's got
that damp, crisp thing going on. I think I've gotten back to liking this
time of year. The last few have been not so good, for reasons I got
basically sorted out this year, so in a way I feel like I'm missing
something by going away (that and Favourite Lady, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been doing a little more Airsoft, when I can. You tend to only
really get the serious players out these days, so it's a little less
annoying. I've also gotten my ticket to &lt;a href="http://www.berget-events.com/"&gt;Berget&lt;/a&gt; for next year. I
didn't go last year because I bought into the lame idea that I have to
bring an entire squad, but I think I'd like to head along even with one
or two people I know this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work has been progressively more involving. I've been getting a lot more
code done recently, and am trying to find a balance between
direction-setting and getting-hands-dirty for the project. I'm
encouraged to find I still like getting my hands dirty, but there's
always last-minute phone calls to encourage people designing software to
not pull the theoretical hot saucepan down on top of themselves which
impinges on Make Time, as we're to call it these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also been looking again at &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Home_automation"&gt;Domotics&lt;/a&gt; -- I've picked up a Scooba,
a few Roombas, and am looking at lawn and garden automation for next
year. I'll do a proper post on this at some point. &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Making-Things-Talk-Practical-Connecting/dp/0596510519/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1290604399&amp;amp;sr=8-1"&gt;Making Things
Talk&lt;/a&gt; is a fascinating read so far, it may be the first paper book I
bring on a plane in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I'm off to California on Sunday. I'm spending a week
with the Analytics development team (I manage the Analytics Frontend SRE
team), and then am in Seattle for 3 days with the Analytics Backend SRE
team. It's my first Mountain View visit in a good long while, almost a
year in fact. It'll be good to see videoconference peeps for realsies
for a change.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="november"></category><category term="update"></category><category term="winter"></category></entry><entry><title>Barcelona</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/barcelona.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-15T16:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-15T16:04:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-11-15:/barcelona.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sagrada Familia has scrubbed up nice, hasn't it? The whole
centre part of it was building site when I was there last, so this is a
step in the awesome direction. We even missed the pope by exactly a
week, as he came along to consecrate it (they need a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sagrada Familia has scrubbed up nice, hasn't it? The whole
centre part of it was building site when I was there last, so this is a
step in the awesome direction. We even missed the pope by exactly a
week, as he came along to consecrate it (they need a level 11
god-botherer to consecrate something this bug, since he's high enough
level to know the spell, and can only cast it once a day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona is still nice. People use the city, which is a far cry from
anything I've seen in Dublin (Dublin has character, but that character
needs a few auld shcoops to loosen itself up and usually finds a way to
wreck anything out of the ordinary).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;November is also a reasonable time to go. It was t-shirt weather
throughout, except for the top of the tourist bus. We didn't get enough
time to do all the touristy bits, but got some successful shopping done
and felt like it was a weekend well-spent nonetheless. We'll probably be
back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roll on the next thing we're doing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="barcelona"></category><category term="blasphemy"></category><category term="city personalities"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Braaains</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/braaains.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-11-06:/braaains.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Work this past week has been a long trial of getting back up to speed
after Tel Aviv. Even though it's pretty much a regular week, catching up
my brain from all the stuff I promised to do, and getting back into the
stuff I was doing when I left …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Work this past week has been a long trial of getting back up to speed
after Tel Aviv. Even though it's pretty much a regular week, catching up
my brain from all the stuff I promised to do, and getting back into the
stuff I was doing when I left had just about happened by today,
basically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently looking into full-spectrum/white lighting, for home and
work. November is usually a bad brain month, in general. This year, I've
been continuing my theme of doing things pro-actively by attempting to
spend at least some of it outside the country (I'll be in Barcelona next
week, and heading to California at the end of the month), and the
aforementioned lighting. I can recommend &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/s?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;search-type=ss&amp;amp;index=kitchen-uk&amp;amp;field-keywords=Androv"&gt;Androv&lt;/a&gt; for cheap bulbs --
their 'dimmable' bulb makes a bold claim I've been unable to reproduce,
but their other stuff is good, and cheap. It makes a discernable
difference to overall mood if I'm working under one for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one bad thing, of course (and the reasons why hotels use low-light
yellow bulbs) is that it shows up every speck of dirt and dust in the
room. Once you can deal with this, I heartily endorse this event or
product. You feel less like you're holed up in a fortress of solitude,
and brighter lights (properly shaded) are in general good for your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been doing other brain stuff recently, which I'll get into. The
moral: making your brain work is damn useful if it's what pays your
bills.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="brain"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="november"></category></entry><entry><title>Tel Aviv</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/tel-aviv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-25T13:19:00+01:00</published><updated>2010-10-25T13:19:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-10-25:/tel-aviv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm spending this week in Israel, in The Company's Tel Aviv
office, doing some ninja work on Analytics production -- a bunch of
stuff gets done out of here, and I'm helping out the nice people here to
keep their services stable and non-annoying. I'm on the 26th floor of a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm spending this week in Israel, in The Company's Tel Aviv
office, doing some ninja work on Analytics production -- a bunch of
stuff gets done out of here, and I'm helping out the nice people here to
keep their services stable and non-annoying. I'm on the 26th floor of a
giant office building, and the view is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tel Aviv beats my record for "Furthest east on a traditional world map",
the previous record held by Dubrovnik. I don't get to do a lot of
touristing this time, but they're at least threatening to bring me to
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesarea"&gt;Caesarea&lt;/a&gt; later in the week. I also get to possibly walk around and
see Jaffa/Yafo on friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn't bring a more beefy camera than the Nexus One, so only a handful
of photos this time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="city personalities"></category><category term="israel"></category><category term="tel aviv"></category><category term="travel"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>Now You're Square, Part Deux</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/now-youre-square-part-deux.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-19T22:22:00+01:00</published><updated>2010-10-19T22:22:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-10-19:/now-youre-square-part-deux.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's getting to be toward the end of the year, time to resurrect the old
monolith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been considering moving to &lt;a href="http://www.wordpress.org/"&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, but wordpress is far too
annoying to set up, and I realise that most people read/skim via RSS and
don't care about delivery mechanisms. It's like putting …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's getting to be toward the end of the year, time to resurrect the old
monolith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been considering moving to &lt;a href="http://www.wordpress.org/"&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, but wordpress is far too
annoying to set up, and I realise that most people read/skim via RSS and
don't care about delivery mechanisms. It's like putting letters you
write to your bank manager in lovely scented paper envelopes you made
yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been doing a lot of travel recently, most recently to Seattle
(again) and Italy. Was also going to be going to Lisbon, but got my
annual dose of brain mush right before. I'm heading to Tel Aviv next
week, Barcelona with a Nice Lady in November, and Seattle in November
too. I'm personally responsible for &lt;a href="http://outsidetheinterzone.blogspot.com/2009/09/mother-nature.html"&gt;crying icebergs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not going to pretend like I'm going to update this more often, but
let's just say I'd like to. I'm feeling a little more like I'd like to
remember some of this stuff, and we won't have USA assorted biscuit tins
full of B&amp;amp;W negatives in 2050.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Log"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="me"></category><category term="revival"></category><category term="update"></category></entry><entry><title>Airport Extreme works THIS WAY. EAT IT.</title><link href="https://log.andvari.net/airport-extreme-works-this-way-eat-it.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-04-07T21:01:00+01:00</published><updated>2010-04-07T21:01:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Dave O'Connor</name></author><id>tag:log.andvari.net,2010-04-07:/airport-extreme-works-this-way-eat-it.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I'm getting increasingly annoyed at Apple's railroading of people's
use cases (no, this has nothing to do with the iPad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only after I started using a Nexus One with android that I realised
how shite the iPhone was in a lot of ways. Case in point: The one …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I'm getting increasingly annoyed at Apple's railroading of people's
use cases (no, this has nothing to do with the iPad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only after I started using a Nexus One with android that I realised
how shite the iPhone was in a lot of ways. Case in point: The one thing
that I wanted my phone to do wasn't implemented yet, so &lt;a href="http://uk.androlib.com/android.application.net-andvari-bluetoothcondition-AwCq.aspx"&gt;I did it&lt;/a&gt;.
The concept of doing that on iPhone without jumping through a ridiculous
number of hoops is alien to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another case in point happened this evening, or at least a symptom of
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd recently gotten a &lt;a href="http://www.soekris.com/net5501.htm"&gt;Soekris net5501&lt;/a&gt; to act as a home dhcp/dns/etc.
server, having gotten tired/bored of just letting the Airport extreme do
everything. I wanted to use DynDNS properly, and I wanted something I
could leave on when I go on business trips (So I can leave power usage
monitoring on, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like a plan, right? So after fiddling with getting the Soekris
installed, I plugged everything in, set up ISC dhcpd and Bind, and then
went to Airport Utility to turn off DHCP on the Airport Extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, you can't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can't actually turn off DHCP, without putting the device into bridge
mode. You literally cannot run a NAT network using an Airport Extreme
where it's not the DHCP server for your LAN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than ditching my Airport on some unsuspecting fanboy and doing
research to find a good 802.11n router, I just set a DHCP pool size of 1
and got on with my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this basically reinforced my increasingly negative opinion of
what Apple is up to these days. Apple products are increasingly not for
people who know what they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a disclaimer, I own an ipod and use a macbook pro as my only computer
for day-to-day use. They work fine, and are great products. Which makes
it a shame that a lot of their other stuff falls down so hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside: here's how to get ISC dhcpd to ignore a certain MAC address if
you have a stupid device you want to talk to another dhcp server:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;host&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;stupidhost&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;hardware&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ethernet&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;DD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;RE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;SS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;deny&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;booting&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech"></category><category term="imported"></category><category term="apple airport dhcp"></category></entry></feed>